<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Releases for MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon</title>
    <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/release</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.9.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.9.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Temporarily backed out the implementation of CSS Cascade Layers for causing layout issues on websites. This will re-land when fixed.</li>
<li>Temporarily backed out the implementation of CSS <code>color-mix</code> for causing crashes. This will re-land when fixed.</li>
<li>Per request from our user base, the blank page with the Pale Moon logo (default for new tabs) will now have an appropriate title (for e.g. identification in tab and window title).</li>
<li>Further improved the &#34;copy as cURL&#34; devtools function. (CVE-2025-11713)</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>There was one reported security issue (CVE-2025-11712) that was investigated but rejected, as adoption of the mitigation for a non-critical sec issue that requires very specific environments to be exploited (with considerable blame for the webmaster) would, in fact, require us to go against some very clear specifications in the HTML standard. Mozilla adopted this primarily for behavioral parity with Chrome. Security impact in the real world was considered to be negligible, and this would have negatively impacted some NPAPI functionality as well.</li>
<li>The vast majority of this release cycle&#39;s Mozilla security issues centered around vulnerabilities due to its multi-process nature and inter-process communication, which are (of course) not applicable to Pale Moon (or any other UXP browser). Multi-process remains mainstream browsers&#39; Achilles&#39; heel, security wise, even years after moving to that application model. It&#39;s ironic that the supposed &#34;big security advantages&#34; of multi-process have been more than undermined by the technology itself.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>115105: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.9.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 22:36:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.9.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.9.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small, critical update to address issues with the browser&#39;s stability and usability due to the 33.9.0 changes to <code>X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff</code> header parsing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>114534: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.9.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.9.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.9.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development, bugfix and security release, focusing primarily on improving web compatibility.<br/>
Special thanks to the students from the University of the Philippines Los Baños for their work on improving CSS in the platform over the summer!</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New features:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented the CSS4 <code>revert</code> keyword.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>clip</code> keyword for <code>overflow</code>. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented axis-shorthand parsing of <code>overflow</code>. This should fix some issues with areas being unscrollable on the web.</li>
<li>Implemented CSS <code>color-mix</code> (RGB and HSL color spaces only).</li>
<li>Implemented CSS <code>@supports(selector(&lt;complex selector&gt;))</code> syntax.</li>
<li>Implemented CSS Cascade Layers <code>@layer</code> support.</li>
<li>Implemented support for CSS <code>clip-path:&lt;geometry-box&gt;</code> without actually supplying a clip path to use. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>overflow-inline</code> and <code>overflow-block</code> CSS properties.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>:autofill</code> CSS pseudo-class. Auto-filled fields will now also be styled by default to indicate autofilling/password manager recall has occurred.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>:focus-visible</code> CSS pseudo-class.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>prefers-reduced-motion</code> CSS media query. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented a minimal version of the <code>visualViewport</code> web API. See implementation notes.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Un-prefixed CSS <code>-moz-user-select</code> and aligned with the user-select CSS4 spec.</li>
<li>Un-prefixed CSS <code>-moz-read-only</code> and <code>-moz-read-write</code> pseudo-classes.</li>
<li>Improved the handling of <code>X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff</code> to align more with the spec and expected behavior on the web.</li>
<li>Added support for FFmpeg 7.0/libavcodec 61.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where sub-properties of CSS <code>border-image</code> would not update when the value they inherit from changes.</li>
<li>Fixed a bug where <code>scrollbar-width</code> was incorrectly treated as an inherited property.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where screen/pixel color depth could potentially be mis-reported on Linux.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with fontconfig on Linux. We now explicitly initialize fontconfig on startup.</li>
<li>Fixed various issues with vpx on PowerPC architectures.</li>
<li>Fixed issues when building ffvpx on architectures without assembly support.</li>
<li>Fixed a memory safety issue in two-position gradient color-stops code.</li>
<li>Changed the way <code>@import</code> rules are processed. They will now be processed in the order of appearance in the importing stylesheet.</li>
<li>Changed how <code>TypedArray</code> constructors handle initialization values, aligning with the ECMAScript spec. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Changed how <code>Cache-control</code> HTTP headers are parsed if multiple headers are present in a response.</li>
<li>Made additional improvements to &#34;Copy as cURL&#34; devtools command.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-10536 and CVE-2025-10533 DiD.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>The <code>clip</code> keyword allows you to specify overflow behavior that acts like a &#34;passe-partout&#34;. This means any overflow will be hidden and content unscrollable.<br/>
Important note: we have strictly followed the standard specification here which may result in issues on some websites if they do not explicitly specify overflow behavior in both axes when using <code>clip</code> as a keyword. <code>clip</code>, per the specification, results in unscrollable hidden content. If the other axis is <code>unset</code>, it will result in visible overflow that is also <em>unscrollable</em> (no scrollbar or mousewheel scrolling). Other browsers <em>may</em> default to scrollable visible overflow, instead. If you are a webmaster, please double-check if you are specifying <code>overflow</code> correctly when you are using <code>clip</code>. Because some of <code>clip</code>&#39;s behavior may be unintuitive at first glance, it serves well to always be explicit in both directions what kind of overflow behavior is desired.</li>
<li>Pale Moon now supports specifying a CSS <code>clip-path</code> with just a geometry box (e.g. <code>border-box</code>) without defining a path. This should fix some websites displaying fully blank pages due to webmasters relying on implied &#34;border-following&#34; clipping when specifying a clip-path this way. Previously, this would result in everything being clipped (which used to be the explicit behaviour when no path definition was provided).</li>
<li>The CSS media query <code>prefers-reduced-motion</code> can be used by webmasters to provide alternative styling of web pages when users indicate that they prefer web pages with less visual motion (e.g. for accessibility considerations for people with vestibular motion disorders). Pale Moon users can indicate this preference with a new option in the browser (Preferences -&gt; Advanced -&gt; tab &#34;General&#34; -&gt; &#34;Prefer reduced visual motion&#34; under Accessibility). Please note that this option doesn&#39;t change how the browser itself handles e.g. animations or CSS; it is up to the webmaster to make use of this CSS feature to cater to visitors with this preference indicator.</li>
<li>We now support a minimal implementation of the <code>visualViewport</code> web API. This API provides webmasters with indicators how much of the visible web pages should be considered &#34;fully visible&#34; to users. This API is primarily designed to cater to mobile traffic where browsers may be impaired by e.g. a camera notch in the screen. Since this isn&#39;t a concern on desktop, we always return a fixed <code>(0,0)</code> value for <code>origin</code> and <code>offset</code>. For other parts of the API, we give back the width/height of the root scrollframe of web content, while for scale we pass forward our dpp resolution (usually 1.0).</li>
<li><code>TypedArray</code> constructors can be passed initialization values to indicate the initial size of the array to create. According to the specced behavior, we should accept most values (anything accepted by <code>ToIndex</code>), even those that make no sense (e.g. a string or <code>undefined</code>). This has now been changed to align with that spec and we no longer throw an error in those cases, and simply return a 0-length typed array instead.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>114531: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.9.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 08:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.8.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor development, security and bugfix release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed the way the address bar focus is handled when navigating to a fragment (#hash or anchor) within an existing URL. It will now re-focus the page the same way a normal address navigation would (resetting the &#34;editing&#34; state, unless the user is actively typing).</li>
<li>Implemented support for the <code>:focus-visible</code> CSS pseudo-class.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential race condition in font tables. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed potential issues with pthread allocations. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed an issue in NSS related to the PKCS12 decoder.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-9181 and several others that do not have a CVE number.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>114525: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 08:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.8.1.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.1.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix update addressing issues with NPAPI plugins not working in v33.8.1.1.<br/>
For safety reasons, plugins are now also by default set to &#34;ask to activate&#34;. It is recommended you keep this default setting and only allow plugins to be activated specifically on the websites you intend to use them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>114511: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.1.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 20:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.8.1.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is an important bugfix update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a crash in the new code introduced in 33.8.1 around <code>&lt;object&gt;</code> restrictions.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression in the styling of the address bar drop-down making links unreadable when highlighted.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>114509: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 07:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.8.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Pale Moon no longer accepts nameless cookies. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Improved the &#34;copy as curl&#34; command in devtools further, partially rolling back the DiD changes in previous versions since we aren&#39;t offering cross-platform commands and it caused potential issues with overzealous escaping.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential use-after-free scenario in the CSS parser.</li>
<li>Fixed uninitialized use of fontconfig scenarios for Linux/GTK.</li>
<li>Adjusted CSP URI reporting to more closely match the current spec and common browser behavior.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential crash in font handling.</li>
<li>Adjusted the size of WASM compiled table size limits to match V8/Gecko.</li>
<li>Increased restrictions on the types of data loads <code>&lt;object&gt;</code> elements are allowed to trigger, to match the fetch spec more closely.</li>
<li>Fixed build issues for PPC architectures.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-8031, CVE-2025-8028 (DiD), CVE-2025-8037 (and related), CVE-2025-8029, and several others that do not have a CVE number.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>From this version forward we no longer accept nameless cookies. If a cookie has no name and starts with an equal sign, it is outright rejected. If a cookie consists only of a string with no equal sign, it is interpreted as a valueless cookie with the name set to the string. This departs from our inherited Mozilla behavior where this was previously treated as a nameless cookie with the string as the value.<br/>
RFC 6265 forbids cookies without an equal sign (§5.2 step 2), but browsers accept them anyway for web compatibility reasons (poor web design). Moreover, §5.2 step 5 explicitly forbids nameless cookies.<br/>
Valueless names also make more sense in web context: <code>Set-cookie:</code> itself supports <code>secure</code> and <code>httponly</code> as valueless attributes, and HTML supports valueless attributes as well.<br/>
Our new behavior therefore makes more logical sense, is closer to the spec and general principles, aligns with webkit/Safari and solves a whole class of potential sec bugs like CVE-2025-8037. Apologies if this causes web compat issues, but it&#39;s the sane thing to do when encountering non-compliant cookies.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>114507: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 15:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.8.0-r2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.0_Release-r2</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">Updated release for build bustage experienced on Tier2+ platforms (Linux/i386 et al).<br/>
Release notes: see the main 33.8.0 release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>113040: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.0_Release-r2</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.8.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development, bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Pale Moon now includes all non-ubiquitous image and media types in the navigation <code>Accept:</code> header, as discussed in the relevant <a href="https://github.com/whatwg/fetch/issues/274" rel="nofollow">whatwg fetch spec issue</a>.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>.toJSON()</code> for <code>DOMRect</code>, <code>DOMPoint</code> and <code>DOMMatrix</code>.</li>
<li>Added a base implementation of the <code>SVGGeometryElement</code> API. This is currently limited to <code>.pathLength</code>, <code>getTotalLength()</code> and <code>getPointAtLength(distance)</code> for SVG paths.</li>
<li>Added a base-64/character validity grammar check for CSP nonces.</li>
<li>Enabled JPEG-XL support unconditionally.</li>
<li>Improved desktop ARM media capabilities.</li>
<li>Improved our handling of CSP checks (multiple improvements surrounding loading principal checks).</li>
<li>Added several Mac-specific file types to be treated as executables.</li>
<li>Updated the emoji font to Unicode 16.0.0. We can now finally have the &#34;tired dev&#34; emoji 🫩!</li>
<li>Updated SQLite library to 3.50.1.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.90.7.1 to fix some issues with some sites due to prior root certificate updates.</li>
<li>Updated code dealing with internal URL rewrites for Youtube.</li>
<li>Changed the Firefox compatibility mode version to 128.</li>
<li>Changed how <code>.click()</code> on <code>&lt;A&gt;</code> elements is handled. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Changed DOMMatrix&#39;s <code>rotate()</code> and <code>rotateSelf()</code> functions to accept 3D rotation instead of 2D, per spec.</li>
<li>Changed CSS parameter animation to round values instead of truncating them, per spec.<br/>
This affects all integer properties (e.g. z-order) and font-stretching.</li>
<li>Changed HTML element attribute parsing to additionally escape <code>&lt;</code> and <code>&gt;</code> characters, per spec.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression in XUL <code>&lt;tree&gt;</code> elements where column selection would omit the first-defined column.</li>
<li>Fixed a minor issue in <code>DOMSVGPoint</code> finity checks.</li>
<li>Fixed some minor platform issues and updated Mac SDK checks.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue when device contrast values would be unset in Mac or Windows+DirectWrite.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in 33.7.2&#39;s updated &#34;Copy as curl&#34; feature which could potentially mangle URLs.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with <code>FontFaceSet</code> loading.</li>
<li>Removed support for very old libavcodec versions (before v58).</li>
<li>Removed the CSP <code>referrer</code> directive as it&#39;s no longer in the spec.</li>
<li>Removed preloading of a number of media libraries on Windows. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Removed the allowance of <code>&lt;A&gt;</code> in image maps. Only <code>&lt;area&gt;</code> is now supported.</li>
<li>Removed several obsolete and unused preferences from about:config.</li>
<li>Removed obsolete NPN preferences and calls. NPN has long since been replaced by ALPN.</li>
<li>Removed obsolete <code>SVGZoomEvent</code> interface and handlers.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-6429, CVE-2025-6424 (DiD) and CVE-2025-6426.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Normally, when a script issues a simulated click on an element, that click is issued on the document the element is in. Unfortunately there has been a perceived bug in mainstream browsers where this didn&#39;t happen on anchors (<code>&lt;A&gt;</code>, hyperlinks) and the browser would navigate even if that anchor was not actually in a web page document (i.e. just created as a reference in scripting). This was eventually made an accepted behaviour in the specification as an exception, describing this bug as expected behavior. Pale Moon has now changed how it handles <code>.click()</code> events on anchors to follow this behavior. This primarily impacts some select &#34;download button&#34; behavior on the web where this behavior quirk for anchors is relied on.</li>
<li>Previously, Pale Moon would preload a number of media .dll files into the browser, causing resource use even if there was no media to be decoded or played back in the browsing session yet. This was primarily done in inherited Mozilla code for EME to work. Since we don&#39;t support in-browser DRM, this preloading is wholly unnecessary and has been removed.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>112568: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.8.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 13:12:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.7.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.7.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Addressed PWN2OWN-2025-1 (out of bounds read or write in promise) DiD</li>
<li>Addressed PWN2OWN-2025-2 (out of bounds read or write when using the ExtractLinearSum optimization) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed potential unexpected behavior in embedded protobuf code. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with potentially uninitialized contrast values when enhanced device contrast values can not be read from the O.S. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed potential sanitization issues with devtools&#39; &#34;Copy as curl&#34; feature.<br/>
It should be noted that we do not currently offer cross-platform &#34;curl&#34; features, so this is another DiD for this release.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>110879: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.7.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 09:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.7.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.7.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a crash dealing with <code>BigInt</code> in Javascript compilation.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.90.7 to pick up a security fix.</li>
<li>Updated devtools to escape some more characters in &#34;Copy as cURL&#34; on POSIX operating systems. (DiD)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>110874: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.7.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 07:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.7.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.7.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented CSS two-location color stop logic. This allows for two-location color stops (<code>color x% y%</code>) in gradients, which is shorthand for <code>color x%, color y%</code> where both colors are equal.</li>
<li>Our minimum GCC version requirement to build is now 9.1.</li>
<li>Improved channel handling when CSP blocks network redirects.</li>
<li>Implemented several fixes for CORS preflight requests.</li>
<li>Added explicit whitelisting from CSP content loading of <code>javascript:</code> scheme URLs.</li>
<li>Updated the ffvpx library to 6.0.1, this time preventing video color range regressions. An update to 6.0 was previously backed out in 33.5.0.</li>
<li>Updated the JPEG-XL library to 0.11.1 to pick up several fixes and improve decoding compatibility of jxl files.</li>
<li>Updated the SQLite library to 3.49.1.</li>
<li>Fixed a spec compliance issue with <code>DOMRect</code> and <code>DOMQuad</code> returning <code>0</code> if <code>NaN</code> was present. We now return <code>NaN</code> in that case, per spec.</li>
<li>Fixed a spec compliance issue with NTLM authentication. We now compute Channel Binding Hashes using the certificate signature&#39;s hash algorithm, per spec.<br/>
Note that particularly weak algorithms are not used and SHA256 will be used as a minimum, instead, in those cases.</li>
<li>Fixed a buildability issue on Mac with XCode 16.3.</li>
<li>Added some additional safety checking to <code>SharedArrayBuffers</code>.</li>
<li>Added some additional safety checking to XSLT compilation and transformation.</li>
<li>Windows only: Added a preference <code>widget.windows.follow_shortcuts_on_file_open</code> to control how Windows File Open dialogs handle shortcut links. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Security bugs addressed: CVE-2025-3028 (DiD) and CVE-2025-3033 (see implementation notes).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Windows only: This version introduces a new (numeric) preference to control how the &#34;Open File&#34; dialogs handle shortcut links in the file system.<br/>
A low-severity security issue (CVE-2025-3033) was found that in some specific circumstances could allow a malicious actor to convince a user to upload an unintended file from their file system with a specially-crafted shortcut file. To mitigate this, a special flag can be passed to File Open dialogs which prevent the dialogs from parsing shortcut links and navigating to target files and folders based on the shortcut file contents. This can be controlled with the newly-added preference. Since this flag, when set, also prevents users from navigating &#34;through&#34; shortcuts to folders (from e.g. the desktop) and would instead open/attach/upload the shortcut file itself, this would be disruptive to many users&#39; workflows. Considering the major usability drawback and the low-severity nature of the security issue (which would require considerable social engineering to pull off), Pale Moon, at least for the time being or until a better solution is found, will continue allowing the following of shortcuts and navigating through them to target folders and files in File Open dialogs. If you are overly cautious, you may want to set this preference to the value 0 which always prevents shortcut parsing and following. For everyone else, just a warning to please stay safe and never follow strange sequences of instructions from strangers that you don&#39;t exactly know what they do (and never take their explanations at face value).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>110702: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.7.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 07:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.6.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.6.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security, bugfix and stability update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Simplified some WASM code generation in the Ion JIT compiler.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in loading external resource maps.</li>
<li>Disabled potentially unsafe attempts at recovering JIT operations.</li>
<li>Fixed some minor linking issues in <code>about:rights</code>.</li>
<li>Updated the embedded emoji font to fix incorrect display of some of the wheelchair emoji.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-1934 (DiD).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>110690: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.6.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 10:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.6.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.6.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is an extra update to mitigate as much of the CloudFlare issues leading to browser hangs and memory issues as possible on the web browser side. Unfortunately CloudFlare still hasn&#39;t pulled their scripts that seem to deliberately cause these issues on Pale Moon and other independent browsers they seem to want to keep from the websites they &#34;protect&#34;. If you are interested in learning more, check out the forum thread where we&#39;re discussing this issue. Once again, please consider reporting any and all occurrences of failing or looping CloudFlare checks on websites to CloudFlare as well as the owners of affected websites (you may have to temporarily use a Chromium-based browser to do this).</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Disabled CSP reporting temporarily to work around memory issues caused by CloudFlare&#39;s scripting. While CSP reporting is important to inform webmasters of issues with their content security policies, not having the browser eat up all memory is more critical. We do intend to re-enable this when the issue is resolved on CloudFlare&#39;s side.</li>
<li>Improved CSS grid performance to avoid exponential calculations and reflows caused by CloudFlare&#39;s scripting. This wasn&#39;t a bug, per se, but could easily lock up with bad scripting if called recursively.</li>
<li>Added a few other small fixes that are tangentially related to the code changes made.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>109715: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.6.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 11:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.6.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.6.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security release.<br/>
Due to the fact that CloudFlare has been causing application crashes that impacts many users, this release has been pulled forward a few days to address these crashes with priority (should be fixed in this release).<br/>
Please note that at the time of publication of this browser version and release notes, even though crashes have been fixed, CloudFlare is denying UXP-based browsers as well as several other independent/smaller browsers access to many websites by way of their malfunctioning &#34;security check&#34; or captcha, with no priority given to actually fix it despite it being denial of service for users of affected browsers. Please consider reporting any and all occurrences of a failing or looping CloudFlare checks on websites to CloudFlare as well as the owners of affected websites (you may have to temporarily use a Chromium-based browser to do this).</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented a content sniffer for ADTS and raw AAC audio.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>AbortSignal.abort()</code> and stub <code>AbortSignal.timeout()</code>.</li>
<li>Unprefixed the <code>:modal</code> CSS pseudo-class and exposed it to content.</li>
<li>Improved efficiency and performance of the Cycle Collector.</li>
<li>Added a check for explicit expectance of a percentage value in CSS HSL for the S and L components.</li>
<li>Updated the cookie storage database to no longer use BaseDomain. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Updated CSS grid handling to no longer apply <code>auto</code> min-sizing when <code>flex</code> max-sizing (browser parity).</li>
<li>Updated the root certificates in the internal trust store.</li>
<li>Updated the Public Suffix List (eTLD) in the browser.</li>
<li>Removed no longer specced URL <code>Constructor(DOMString url, URL base)</code>.</li>
<li>Restored unofficial branding to what it was before (&#34;New Moon&#34; instead of &#34;Browser&#34;).</li>
<li>Changed the default Firefox Compatibility user-agent version to 115.0.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where cloned <code>&lt;audio&gt;</code> or <code>&lt;video&gt;</code> elements would not respect the original element&#39;s muted state.</li>
<li>Fixed a number of bugs and spec compliance issues in <code>WebCrypto</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed installer application naming issue causing failure to detect running application.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when <code>Interval</code> handlers are present in scripts that are automatically terminated due to excessive runtime.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in JS Structured Cloning when the input would be bogus (CloudFlare-triggered crash).</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in the XSLT stylesheet importing code.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.90.6 (custom) to pick up several security fixes.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-1009.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>When updating the browser to this version, a one-way upgrade of the cookie database in your browser profile is performed on first start. The new cookie database is not backwards compatible, meaning <strong>you cannot use the browser profiles that have been upgraded by this version or later with any prior versions of the browser without data loss</strong>.<br/>
This is generally the case as most upgrades of user data storage are one-way, but having all your cookies cleared unintentionally is something most people prefer to avoid, hence this warning and a general reminder of profile migrations to newer versions that may happen with any (non-minor) browser upgrade.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100701: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.6.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.5.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.5.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed the way cookies are handled internally to fix an issue with cookie database corruption as a result of updates to domain suffixes.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Alternative-Services protocol negotiation.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential crash scenario with Structured Clone operations. (<em>DiD</em>)</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with line breaking if out of memory.</li>
<li>Fixed a rare crash with opportunistic encryption.</li>
<li>Minor code cleanup.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2025-0239 and CVE-2025-0238.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100653: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.5.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 23:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.5.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.5.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security release.<br/>
<strong>Note:</strong> Intel Mac builds are now &#34;ad hoc&#34; signed instead of unsigned, which should solve potential issues with newer macOS while still being compatible with old OS X. If you experience issues, please post in the Mac board on the forum for support.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented Regular Expression &#34;match indices&#34; (/d) feature.</li>
<li>Added a way to programmatically clear the DNS cache in the browser, and added a button to the UI for it in <a href="about:networking" rel="nofollow">about:networking</a>.</li>
<li>Updated handling of referrer policies to adhere to the updated spec.</li>
<li>CSS font <code>variations</code> keywords no longer throw an error. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>CSS <code>border-radius</code> will now also apply to element <code>outline</code>s.</li>
<li>Improved the display of amount of cached web content in preferences when cache is being cleared.</li>
<li>Improved the installer AVX check to skip on early versions of Windows 10 (which don&#39;t support it).</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.90.5 (unofficial) to pick up some security fixes.</li>
<li>Refreshed the built-in list of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_Suffix_List" rel="nofollow">effective top-level domains</a>.</li>
<li>Fixed several application crashes.</li>
<li>Reduced unnecessary debug/informative messages in release builds (WebGL and CSP).</li>
<li>Backed out building against ffmpeg 6.0 and ffvpx 6.0 for causing a video playback regression on full-range videos (levels 0-255).</li>
<li>Cleaned up a large amount of leftover Boot2Gecko code, simplifying code paths throughout the code base.</li>
<li>From this version forward we also publish language packs for Persian (Farsi), Hindi, Kannada and Vietnamese.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-11693 and CVE-2024-11704 (DiD).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>The CSS font variations keywords (<code>woff2-variations</code>, <code>truetype-variations</code>, etc.) allow webmasters to indicate format hints for <code>@font-face</code> font resources so authors can provide alternative resources for browsers that don&#39;t support <code>tech(variations)</code>. The intent of these hints is to provide an alternate font with variations in addition to regular fonts without. Unfortunately, some webmasters don&#39;t indicate a base font the variation font face would be an alternate for, which resulted in Pale Moon throwing an error on the only <code>@font-face</code> <code>src</code> entry provided, in turn having the web font not being loaded at all (because no valid entry was found), breaking website layout. From this version onwards, we parse the <code>-variations</code> keywords allowing variation alternative font-faces to be loaded, even if no base font was specified. To webmasters only supplying <code>@font-face entries</code> with <code>variations</code> keywords: please understand the intent of this CSS 4 spec and always provide a base font entry (graceful fallback).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100595: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.5.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 10:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.4.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.4.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added a processor check to the 64-bit installer for Windows to check for AVX.<br/>
Note: this check does not work on Window 7/8/8.1 and will allow installations on non-AVX processors there.<br/>
Note: if you are running Windows 10 before build 2004 (before 20H1), this check may fail on AVX-capable CPUs and prevent installation.</li>
<li>Improved handling of multipart/mixed documents. (CVE-2024-10461 and CVE-2016-2816) DiD</li>
<li>Addressed CVE-2024-10463.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100582: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.4.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 11:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.4.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.4.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to address two important issues:</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Extension compatibility issues with the ghostbuster (leading to tab handling problems).</li>
<li>Windows 7 compatibility issues in 32-bit builds on some systems (leading to application UI paint failures/black window).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100572: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.4.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.4.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.4.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Introduced the &#34;ghostbuster&#34; concept; this is an automated internal mechanism to attempt cleanup of particularly problematic web content after a tab or window is closed. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Added support for the PROT_MPROTECT security feature on targets that use it (notably PaX and NetBSD).</li>
<li>Implemented preferences to give the user control over the Same-Origin Policy (SOP) and CORS preflight. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Improved buildability on NetBSD and Altivec architectures.</li>
<li>Fixed building issues on Apple Silicon Mac with XCode 16.</li>
<li>Added workarounds for non-standard MSE/WebM/VPx encoding on YouTube that could cause video buffering and halting issues.</li>
<li>Dev: Changed the default credentials mode for module scripts from &#39;omit&#39; to &#39;same-origin&#39;, aligning with mainstream.</li>
<li>Dev: Implemented <code>getTransform</code> and <code>setTransform</code> with <code>DOMMatrix</code> arguments.</li>
<li>Dev: Implemented ES2023 Hashbang grammar proposal.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with JavaScript&#39;s <code>StructuredClone</code>.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-9396.</li>
<li>Rejected: CVE-2024-9398 (properly informing the user about attempts to use unhandled protocols by web pages is considered more important than potential determination whether a handler for such a protocol is installed)</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>
<p dir="auto">When very complex &#34;modern&#34; websites get closed by the user, it is possible that the browser is unable to properly release all the resources attached to it, especially those resources, modules and scripts that were part of Shadow DOM or complex interlinked module scripts. This can then result in &#34;detached&#34; web content and scripts that continue to use memory, have active event listeners and loaded scripts. Mainstream browsers are less affected by this as their multi-process setups will effectively &#34;throw the baby out with the bath water&#34; by simply killing the relevant content process. Since we don&#39;t have that luxury of a lazy solution to an architectural problem, we need to handle these so-called &#34;ghost windows&#34; resulting from this problem internally without restarting the browser process. This version of Pale Moon introduces the &#34;ghostbuster&#34; concept to try and address this: an automated, internal mechanism that periodically checks for the existence of ghost windows and severs links of them, so that garbage/cycle collection can come in afterwards and release the resources, hopefully preventing browser slowdowns and inflated memory usage over time. If this, for some reason, causes issues for you, you can disable the ghostbuster by setting the preference <code>browser.ghostbuster.enabled</code> to <code>false</code>. Also please report (in detail) on the forum about the issue you&#39;re having if flipping this preference to false resolves it, so we can look into improving this new feature.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p dir="auto">By user request, primarily for advanced power users who need this for their local setups, 2 new preferences were introduced to control how the browser deals with same-origin and CORS.</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li><code>security.same_origin_policy.enabled</code>, when set to <code>false</code>, will completely disable checking if scripts are allowed to be loaded based on the same-origin policy. Security warning: this is a really bad idea on the open web and you should never blanket disable the Same-Origin Policy check in a web browser for normal use.</li>
<li><code>content.cors.bypass_preflight_request</code>, when set to <code>true</code>, will no longer send CORS preflight requests or check preflight responses and always allow cross-origin requests. Note that this kind of request is normally only made if sending a request to a server might result in data changes server-side (e.g. <code>POST</code>). This preference only does something when CORS is already disabled; provided primarily for specific corner cases where CORS is disabled and preflight checks (providing an extra safety net for server data) need to be shut off too.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>There are dragons hiding in these two preferences. Please handle them responsibly.</strong></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100571: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.4.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 08:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.3.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.3.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor security and bugfix update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Backed out support for FFmpeg 7.0/libavcodec 61 (Linux) due to it causing a major regression in WebAudio (broken on all platforms). This is being worked on to re-land at a later date.</li>
<li>Restricted the <code>NotifyPaintEvent</code> interface to chrome code only; there is no reason (other than potential tracking/fingerprinting) to have this accessible from content.</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable issue in JavaScript (<code>FetchName</code>).</li>
<li>Fixed a code correctness issue in XPConnect when creating sandboxes. (DiD)</li>
<li>Added a warning for using externally handled usenet protocols.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-8383 and CVE-2024-8381.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100337: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.3.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 08:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.3.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.3.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Important notes with this version:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>From this version forward, all 64-bit releases require a processor with AVX capabilities! Please keep en eye on the forum for announcements of 64-bit SSE builds by the community if you are on particularly old or otherwise limited hardware that does not support AVX.</li>
<li>For Linux users: Starting with this version, our binaries are built with gcc 11 on a still conservative but more modern build platform (Oracle Linux 8). As a result, there may be some lib incompatibilities if you are still running on a particularly old distro for some reason. While we try to serve as broad of a Linux base as possible with our binaries, our lowest common denominator will occasionally shift to newer distros as a result of O.S. life cycles, compiler capabilities and available libraries.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented the bulk of the CSS &#34;cascade layers&#34; spec (<code>@layer{}</code>). This implementation is not 100% complete yet, but should satisfy common use of CSS cascade layers on the web.</li>
<li>Implemented support for <code>Sec-Fetch-*</code> headers, implementing another mechanism to deal with site security. See this part of the spec for a primer on what this does.</li>
<li>Added support for FFmpeg 7.0 / libavcodec 61 (Linux).</li>
<li>Pale Moon will now look up hosts in DNS ahead of time to make page navigation smoother. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Pale Moon will now block access to the reserved address 0.0.0.0 on non-Windows operating systems. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Dev: Aligned rounding behavior and precision ranges of <code>toFixed</code> and related functions with the spec. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Dev: Aligned <code>isTrusted</code> for <code>PostMessage</code> and <code>BroadcastChannel</code> with expected values on the web. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Dev: Added the <code>navigator.webdriver</code> attribute for web compatibility (always false in Pale Moon as we do not support browser automation APIs).</li>
<li>Re-implemented the Durstenfeld shuffle for plugin enumeration that was unfortunately dropped with one of our past rebases, to strengthen fingerprinting resistance.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with character clusters (e.g. for text selection) resulting from a regression surrounding our improvements for emoji handling.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with setting DOM color values. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Slightly improved password form handling, detecting previously unsupported field orders.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.90.4.</li>
<li>Updated our emoji font to 15.1.2 (Unicode 15.1 with some additional extras/updates).</li>
<li>Code cleanup:
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Removed unused code related to the (incomplete) FoxEye experiment.</li>
<li>Removed support code for LibAV and (very) old versions of FFmpeg. We require libavcodec 58 or later (FFmpeg 4.0+) from this version forward (Linux).</li>
<li>Removed click event dispatching code that is no longer relevant.</li>
<li>Cleaned up internal macro use in CSS code (this does not impact any exposed APIs or code).</li>
<li>Removed the hidden <code>network.dns.disablePrefetchFromHTTPS</code> pref. DNS prefetching should not be treated differently for http and https.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-7531.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Pale Moon will now pre-emptively look up the internet addresses in DNS for website navigation (e.g. from links). This speeds up navigation as there will be no delay for DNS lookups when users navigate to a new host or domain from the visited page. Please note that this only deals with DNS (i.e.: looking up the addresses of websites in the domain name system) and Pale Moon will not pre-emptively connect to the servers in question; it will just have the addresses for them ready in case the user decides to navigate to them.<br/>
For some people, this may still be seen as a privacy issue (e.g. when the DNS server operated within an organization is tightly monitored for &#34;unwanted traffic&#34;) as it will regularly fire DNS lookups for hosts or domains the user doesn&#39;t actually visit, so if this is a concern for you and you wish to revert to our previous behavior, go to Preferences -&gt; Advanced -&gt; tab &#34;Network&#34;, and uncheck &#34;Prefetch DNS lookups&#34;.</li>
<li>Pale Moon will no longer allow connecting to the &#34;this machine&#34; special reserved address <code>0.0.0.0</code> (and IPv6 equivalents <code>[::]</code>/<code>[::0.0.0.0]</code>) on operating systems other than Windows. This is to mitigate potentially unrestricted access to local resources on UNIX-like operating systems due to the way the network stack operates there. If needed for your use case, you can control this behavior through the preference <code>network.dns.blockQuad0</code> -- if set to true, any attempt to connect to the reserved addresses will result in an error.</li>
<li>We aligned behavior of number conversions with what is generally expected on the web by mainstream browser engines and/or updated specs. Specifically, <code>toFixed</code> no longer accepts negative precision ranges, and <code>toExponential</code> will now round up at the midpoint in the decimal significand.</li>
<li>Initially, the mechanisms <code>BroadcastChannel</code> and <code>MessagePort</code> implicitly called for dispatched events to not be trusted, but since browsers marked them as trusted, this was in conflict with the spec. Eventually, the spec for this was changed to make them trusted in this case. Pale Moon now follows this behavior as well.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100278: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.3.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 09:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.2.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.2.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a crash in CSS grid layout.</li>
<li>Set hidden HTML elements to actually always be hidden.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.90.3.</li>
<li>Updated SQLite to 3.46.0.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with setting of cookies.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Linux IPC code.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with DNS prefetching (disabled by default).</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-6611, CVE-2024-6612 <em>DiD</em> and several others (mostly <em>DiD</em>) that do not have a CVE number assigned.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100059: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.2.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 19:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.2.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.2.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, stability and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Note:</strong> Mac builds have switched to Xcode 15 and are now cross-compiled from Apple silicon for Intel targets. While the resulting builds have been tested on a few Intel Mac systems, this is a big build change, so please get in touch through our forum if you experience any issues with these builds on Mac.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New features:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented the missing parts of the html5 <code>&lt;dialog&gt;</code> element, including modal handling and custom backdrops.</li>
<li>Implemented courser, user-configurable granularity for the canvas poisoning anti-fingerprinting measure. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented new CSS viewport units <code>svw</code>, <code>svh</code>, <code>svmin</code>, <code>svmax</code>, <code>lvw</code>, <code>lvh</code>, <code>lvmin</code>, <code>lvmax</code>, <code>dvw</code>, <code>dvh</code>, <code>dvmin</code> and <code>dvmax</code>.</li>
<li>Implemented new CSS logical viewport units <code>vb</code>, <code>vi</code>, <code>svb</code>, <code>svi</code>, <code>lvb</code>, <code>lvi</code>, <code>dvb</code> and <code>dvi</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Removed the archaic and wholly outdated FIPS security module code.</li>
<li>Removed the archaic DBM support code for storing of passwords in DBM format files.</li>
<li>Removed the <code>-moz</code> prefix from <code>-moz-fit-content</code>, aligning with the current CSS standard <code>fit-content</code> value.</li>
<li>Updated our build system by adopting parts of the old autoconf 2.13 as maintained code. autoconf 2.13 is no longer a build requirement. If you build from source, you may want to review your dependencies with this change.</li>
<li>Fixed issues when building with GCC 14.* and Clang 16.*.</li>
<li>Fixed issues with emoji sequence clusters causing incorrect rendering of emoji glyphs in some cases.</li>
<li>Made some arguments to the legacy <code>XPathEvaluator</code>/<code>XPathExpression</code> interfaces optional for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when reporting JavaScript module exporting errors.</li>
<li>Updated checking of special cookie prefixes to be case-insensitive in accordance with the current RFC 6265 (bis-11+).</li>
<li>Fixed issues with external protocol handlers.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where autocomplete pop-ups would stay open in some circumstances.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with potentially bad file names being entered by the user to &#34;Save As...&#34;.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes and race conditions.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-5699, CVE-2024-5702 <em>DiD</em>, CVE-2024-5690, CVE-2024-5698 <em>DiD</em>, CVE-2024-5688 <em>DiD</em>, CVE-2024-5692 and several other security issues (some more <em>DiD</em>) that do not have CVE numbers assigned to them.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>While we have had canvas data poisoning as an option for a very long time (we introduced it as a concept), it was pointed out that having a fast rotation on the poisoning leading to new and unique canvas hashes every time a user would navigate was a red flag to trackers that poisoning is being employed, mitigating its intent. A different implementation of canvas poisoning was created that will still provide human-imperceptible data manipulation of canvases leading to bogus hashes for trackers, but now in such a way that this hash will not change for a courser, but variable time frame. This time frame defaults to 5 minutes in this release, which may be tweaked in the future if necessary, but is also entirely user-configurable between 1 second and 8 hours with the preference <code>canvas.poisondata.interval</code> (indicated in seconds).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>100046: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.2.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 10:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.1.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor security and stability update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Made the nonce length for http digest auth configurable.</li>
<li>Fixed various potential issues with font loading, parsing and handling.</li>
<li>Cleaned up error reporting for workers and normalized error messages.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-4772 <em>DiD</em>, CVE-2024-4771, CVE-2024-4769 and CVE-2024-4770.</li>
<li>We&#39;ve switched back to an older toolchain (17.3) for compiling 32-bit Windows binaries (again) to hopefully address some of the intermittent stability issues people continued to have on later Microsoft compiler versions when running on older hardware.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>99338: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 01:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.1.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.1.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, stability and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New features:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented support for single-use <code>&lt;link rel=preload&gt;</code> meta tag. This implementation allows use of it without specifying a second <code>&lt;link rel={type}&gt;</code> meta tag to actually load the linked document which was originally intended for this tag (to hint to a browser it should pre-load the document for fast painting).</li>
<li>Implemented CSP v3 keywords <code>script-src-elem</code>, <code>script-src-attr</code>, <code>style-src-elem</code> and <code>style-src-attr</code>.</li>
<li>Enabled the use of html5&#39;s <code>&lt;dialog&gt;</code> by default. While this is not yet a complete implementation, use of it in the wild dictated we enable this early. The implementation should functionally suffice for usage seen so far.</li>
<li>Added support for Emoji 15.1.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>webkitURL</code> legacy <code>window</code> alias for URL for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Implemented CSS shorthands <code>margin-block</code>, <code>margin-inline</code>, <code>padding-block</code> and <code>padding-inline</code>.</li>
<li>Added support for querying CPU capabilities (SSE2/AVX/AVX2) to the <code>Navigator</code> interface. For privacy reasons this is not exposed to the web, but can be used by extensions.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed broken mousewheel scrolling if building with <code>--disable-npapi</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed a minor issue with XUL tree display in some circumstances.</li>
<li>Dev: Aligned canvas <code>Path2D.addPath</code> with the updated spec. It now supports <code>DOMMatrix</code> as opposed to <code>SVGMatrix</code>.</li>
<li>Removed Stylo (Gecko Rust style system) leftovers from the source tree.</li>
<li>Fixed a few potential emoji display issues.</li>
<li>Fixed some issues with workers.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with ctrl+c copying in devtools.</li>
<li>Fixed crashes when run under WINE because of its lack of support for <code>IDXGIKeyedMutex</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when dealing with a specific (unmaintained) extension.</li>
<li>Added <code>.xrm-ms</code> files to the executable warning list on Windows.</li>
<li>Added sanity checks on http/2 header sizes.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue in the JavaScript JIT compiler.</li>
<li>Pulled a few fixes from upstream for the OpenType Sanitizer.</li>
<li>Added a fix to avoid a potential issue when assigning a media data buffer.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-3863, CVE-2024-3302, CVE-2024-3857 (DiD), CVE-2024-3859 and CVE-2024-3861 (DiD).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>99103: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.1.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.0.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.0.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor security and stability release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed an issue with attributes on duplicate html tags.</li>
<li>Aligned the behavior of internal pointer structures to be more uniform. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Security issue addressed: CVE-2024-2610</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>95414: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.0.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 11:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Removed site-specific override for Amazon.com due to breakage.</li>
<li>Fixed script timeout values that were inadvertently overridden in branding.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where empty MIME type registrations would break some parts of the UI.</li>
<li>(Linux only) Pasting URLs to content now by default does not navigate to that URL.</li>
<li>If content-paste-navigation is enabled (via <code>middlemouse.contentLoadURL</code>), navigation is now restricted to pasting to active body type elements (to prevent unwanted navigation when pasting URLs to input boxes, for example).</li>
<li>Fixed a problem with JS modules preventing <code>ExportEntries</code> from working.</li>
<li>(Linux only) Fixed a build issue when building with a system-supplied cairo library (unsupported).</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where workers could lock up the browser with <code>SetInterval</code> with an out-of-bounds (too small) value. This is now clamped to 4ms matching the HTML spec.</li>
<li>Fixed a few usability issues with the built-in developer tools.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential crash in web workers.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential overflow issue in image maps.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential security issue with multi-part/mixed content (CVE-2024-1551).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">(from this point forward we will no longer list UXP Mozilla security patch summaries as they are mostly irrelevant)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>91135: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 08:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 33.0.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.0.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a new milestone release. It involves over 250 commits, of which the most important ones are highlighted here.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New features:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented a restricted version of the asynchronous clipboard API (<code>navigator.clipboard</code>). This API is restricted to <strong>writing only</strong> for obvious security considerations. It supports both <strong>plaintext</strong> and the standard <strong>DataTransfer</strong> methods. We did <em>not</em> implement the reinvented wheel concept of <code>ClipboardItem</code> objects.</li>
<li>Implemented support for SHA-2 (SHA-256/SHA-512/etc.) signatures for OCSP stapled responses.</li>
<li>Implemented an option (Found in <em>Preferences -&gt; Content -&gt; Media tab</em> (new this version)) to restrict DOM full-screen mode to the existing browser window.</li>
<li>Implemented several options in a new preferences tab (<em>Preference -&gt; Privacy -&gt; Tracking</em>) to allow users to more easily control several privacy-impacting features, namely poisoning of canvas data (to prevent fingerprinting), and enabling of Performance observers (a developer feature) that some websites rely on for their operation.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>PromiseRejectionEvent</code>. Although this is rarely actually used, some common JS libraries (you know who you are!) use it as a feature level canary and start loading (broken!) Promise shims if it is not found, causing compatibility issues and broken websites due to the shims.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Aligned microtasks and Promises scheduling with the current spec and expected behavior.</li>
<li>We now no longer send <code>click</code> events to top levels of the document hierarchy when using non-primary buttons (use <code>auxclick</code>, instead, to capture these events).</li>
<li>Greatly improved the performance of box shadows.</li>
<li>Greatly improved the performance of file/data uploads over HTTP/2 (most of the secure websites out there).</li>
<li>Fixed several issues related to focus and content selection.</li>
<li>Fixed issues with the use of <code>focus-within</code> caused by unexpected processing of DOM events.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with CSP not behaving as-expected when using <code>importScripts()</code>, and fixed a number of additional CSP-related issues.</li>
<li>Fixed a web compatibility issue with CORS preflights not sending the original request&#39;s referrer policy or referrer header.</li>
<li>Fixed a spec compliance issue with <code>StructuredClone</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash due to clamping code introduced for <code>SetInterval</code> and <code>SetTimeout</code> timers.</li>
<li>Fixed crashes when dynamic imports are canceled (e.g. by navigation).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Other changes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed <code>&lt;input type=file&gt;</code> to now have its <code>.files</code> property be <em>writable</em> following a spec change and recommendation.</li>
<li>We are now requiring and building against the C++17 language standard.</li>
<li>Updated the in-tree ffvpx lib to 6.0.</li>
<li>Added a preference to allow users to completely disable reporting of CSP errors to webmasters. Using this is strongly discouraged as it will provide essential troubleshooting information to webmasters setting up CSP, and does not pose a privacy issue, but for those who really want it, it can now be fully disabled. The preference is <code>security.csp.reporting.enabled</code>.</li>
<li>Updated the <code>IntersectionObserver</code> interface to now also accept documents for the observer root instead of only HTML elements.</li>
<li>Cleaned up various bits of code surrounding GMP, memory allocation, system libraries, vestigial Android code, freetype2 and developer tools.</li>
<li>Improved efficiency of handling D3D textures.</li>
<li>Added initial and experimental Mac PowerPC and Big Endian support.</li>
<li>Changed the behavior of hung scripts. We now automatically terminate them instead of presenting the user with a dialog box (which may or may not show in a reasonable time if the browser is too busy trying to process the hung script). If you prefer the old behavior, uncheck the box &#34;Automatically stop non-responsive scripts&#34; in <em>Preferences -&gt; Content -&gt; General</em></li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2024-0746, CVE-2024-0741, CVE-2024-0743 DiD, CVE-2024-0750 DiD, and CVE-2024-0753.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 3 fixed, 2 DiD, 12 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>87666: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/33.0.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 11:25:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.5.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.<br/>
Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays to all!</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Removed the standard Twitter/X user-agent override because they decided to block us on it.</li>
<li>Added preferences for the user to control whether or not the tab page title should be included in the window title or not. In Private Browsing mode, the default is now to not show the title in the window. This was done to avoid potential leakage to system logs (e.g. GNOME shell logs or Windows event logs) of websites visited through the recorded window title. The new preferences are <code>privacy.exposeContentTitleInWindow</code> and <code>privacy.exposeContentTitleInWindow.pbm</code> for normal mode and Private Browsing mode, respectively.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes in DOM and relating to dynamic JavaScript module imports.</li>
<li>Removed a restriction on Fetch preflight redirects, following a spec update.</li>
<li>Improved the handling of web workers if they get aborted mid-action.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-6863, CVE-2023-6858 and several others that do not have a CVE number.</li>
<li><em>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 4 fixed, 2 DiD, 1 rejected (which was DiD at best), 1 postponed (low risk), 22 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>82354: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 13:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.5.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor development and security update.<br/>
<em>Important: as of this version, our beta FreeBSD binaries require at least FreeBSD 13.</em></p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Restricted protocol fallback for TLS. Pale Moon no longer (by default) allows TLS 1.3 to fall back to earlier protocol versions during the initial handshake.</li>
<li>Reverted the addition of <code>browser.bookmarks.openInTabClosesMenu</code> due to behavioral issues with menus.<br/>
If you desire the intended behavior, please use an extension instead.</li>
<li>We no longer support the <code>data:</code> protocol inside SVG&#39;s <code>&lt;use&gt;</code> statements.</li>
<li>Enabled more validation/error checking for WebGL on Windows to prevent potential crashes.</li>
<li>Improved secure context checking for iframes.</li>
<li>Fixed the handling of relative paths in URLs starting with multiple forward slashes.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-6204, CVE-2023-6210, CVE-2023-6209 and CVE-2023-6205 DiD</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 3 fixed, 1 DiD, 14 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>79524: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 07:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.5.0 (SunOS)</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.0_Release-SunOS</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">SunOS release of 32.5.0</p>
<p dir="auto">Separate release for using updated UXP as its state for SunOS was broken with the initial 32.5.0 release commits.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>76212: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.0_Release-SunOS</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 14:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.5.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development and security update. And a Happy Halloween to everyone who celebrates! <span class="emoji" aria-label="jack-o-lantern">🎃</span><span class="emoji" aria-label="ghost">👻</span><span class="emoji" aria-label="bat">🦇</span></p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added an initial implementation of the ReadableStreams API, improving web compatibility with sites that apparently use this API in utilitarian fashion.</li>
<li>Added support for transparency in WebM videos for the edge case of using <code>&lt;video&gt;</code> elements for transparent animated images. Major caveat: this will massively impact performance of video playback if an alpha channel is present in the video.</li>
<li>Added support for <code>crypto.randomUUID</code> to allow website scripting to generate random UUIDs (universally unique identifiers) through the WebCrypto interface.</li>
<li>By user request, added a preference <code>browser.bookmarks.openInTabClosesMenu</code> (default true) to allow users to configure if they want to keep the bookmarks menu open if they open bookmarks from it in a new tab (by middle-clicking or Ctrl-clicking). The default behavior is to close the bookmarks menu like any other menu when an option in it is clicked.</li>
<li>Removed the user-agent override for Netflix, since they have stopped supporting the Silverlight browser plugin. Pale Moon no longer has a way to provide Netflix DRM-controlled playback with them dropping it, so there is no longer a reason to try and force compatibility.</li>
<li>Updated the user-agent override for Spotify. While it is possible to use the website with this, it suffers from the same DRM issue and not all media will be playable (only non-encumbered media can be played in Pale Moon like podcasts). Your mileage may vary.</li>
<li>Implemented timer nesting and clamping for workers, preventing timer hangs on bad website code.</li>
<li>Improved handling of drawing SVG images on canvases without explicit width or height attributes. We now follow the <em>css-sizing-3 Intrinsic Sizes</em> spec.</li>
<li>Improved performance of our memory allocator.</li>
<li>Updated libvpx to 1.6.1.</li>
<li>Cleaned up and updated some media playback code.</li>
<li>Removed the inclusion of GMP (Gecko Media Plugin) support from Pale Moon, as it was only in use for EME/DRM and WebRTC, neither of which we support.</li>
<li>Removed the last vestiges of EME/DRM code from UXP, since this will never be supported in any application building on it due to the media industry&#39;s draconic policies around FOSS.</li>
<li>Removed <em>simd.js</em>, moving actually used SIMD handling to C++.</li>
<li>Removed the use of libav in our source, replacing its supply of FFT with the equivalent from FFMpeg.</li>
<li>Fixed potential type confusion in IonMonkey due to 3-byte opcodes.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with tooltips persisting even if the browser window would have lost focus.</li>
<li>Fixed <code>PerformanceObserver</code> navigation and resource timing (default disabled for privacy); our implementation now fully passes conformance tests.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where top-level SVG images would not be correctly clipped by positioned elements, giving the impression of wrong z-ordering as the SVG would overlap other elements.</li>
<li>Dev: Updated <code>setInterval</code> to fall back to 0 if no duration is supplied.</li>
<li>Dev: Updated <code>ResizeObserver</code> to a recent spec change, now returning an array of results for <code>borderBoxSize</code> and <code>contentBoxSize</code> instead of an object.</li>
<li>Dev: Updated <code>Intl.NumberFormat</code> and <code>DefaultNumberOption()</code> to follow spec updates. Most importantly for web compatibility, we now allow the &#34;maximumFractionDigits&#34; option in <code>Intl.NumberFormat</code> to be less than the default minimum fraction digits for the chosen locale, following the general consensus in TC39 around this issue.</li>
<li>Increased leniency (removed upper limit) of GLSL versions as they tend to be fully backwards compatible.</li>
<li>Fixed various crashes.</li>
<li>Added a safeguard to the <em>sec-gpc</em> header (Global Privacy Control) so it cannot be inadvertently overwritten.</li>
<li>Security fixes: addressed CVE-2023-5722, CVE-2023-5723, CVE-2023-5724, CVE-2023-5727 and several other issues without a CVE number assigned to them.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 6 fixed, 2 DiD, 19 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>74998: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.5.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 18:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.4.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.4.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed an issue in BigInt <code>typedArray</code> costructors.</li>
<li>Added some safety checks for Performance Observers.</li>
<li>Fixed JSON BigInt regressions.</li>
<li>Fixed missing BigInt increment/decrement operations.</li>
<li>Added WASM sign extension opcodes.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with dead Promise wrappers in JavaScript <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Alternative Services <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed an issue with libvpx (address CVE-2023-5217) <em>DiD</em></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>69451: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.4.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 20:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.4.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.4.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a point release update to address a critical security vulnerability.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>66647: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.4.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 08:32:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.4.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.4.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update, further improving web compatibility and fixing bugs.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented the <code>BigInt</code> primitive type for JavaScript. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>Big(U)Int64</code> array support.</li>
<li>Implemented ergonomic brand checks for JavaScript class fields.</li>
<li>Aligned the Performance API with the Timeline v2 spec.</li>
<li>Aligned the handling of flex/grid percentages resolving against the parent with other browsers. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Added or updated several user-agent overrides for problematic websites.</li>
<li>Added 2 preferences to allow users to disable CSS animations and transitions. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Improved compatibility with MacOS 14.</li>
<li>Fixed an important, intermittent JavaScript crash related to garbage collection.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes.</li>
<li>Fixed several debug build related issues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue building on SunOS related to the spelling library.</li>
<li>Developer: Added ASan support for building with MSVC.</li>
<li>Added the <code>.xll</code> file extension to the executable extensions list.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: several potential security issues that do not have a CVE number. DiD</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 1 fixed, 3 DiD, 17 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>The <code>BigInt</code> primitive (base number format) in JavaScript allows JavaScript to handle excessively large integers (whole numbers). This primitive is especially useful for specialized scientific applications that need very large yet accurate numbers, but has seen widespread adoption for an as of yet unknown reason as part of web frameworks, causing general web compatibility issues for Pale Moon when scripts expect <code>BigInt</code> support and instead have an error thrown. We have now implemented this primitive for use so we no longer have compatibility issues with these frameworks. It is still unknown why <code>BigInt</code> is in use there and for what.<br/>
<strong>Critical note:</strong> <code>BigInt</code> might be tempting to consider for JS-backed cryptography but this is very ill-advised, as <code>BigInt</code> operations are, by their nature, not constant-time and allow timing and side-channel attacks.</li>
<li>Flex and grid item sizes in percentages would previously be resolved against the parent like other elements, according to a very long-standing practice that stems from the Internet Explorer days. Mainstream browsers have, however, made an exception for flex items and grid items to no longer do this. We have now made the same exception for these types of elements which should solve layout issues on some websites (notably reserving too much space for items, often resulting in very large areas of whitespace or items being pushed out of view).</li>
<li>Two preferences were added (<code>layout.css.animation.enabled</code> and <code>layout.css.transition.enabled</code>) to allow users to completely disable CSS-based animations and transition effects. This was a request by users as both a performance and accessibility consideration. Please note that in some cases, disabling animations and transitions <em>may</em> have an impact on final web page layout, so you may run into some issues when disabling these animations and transitions as the web pages were designed to use them.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>65611: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.4.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.3.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.3.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update, further improving web compatibility.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added the (hidden) preference <code>browser.history.menuMaxResults</code> to allow users to control how many history entries are listed in the menu. Setting this to <code>0</code> will hide history menu entries altogether, and any positive number configures how many entries the entries are limited to. The default if not defined is 15.</li>
<li>Switched C++ language level used to C++14 on all platforms.</li>
<li>Web compatibility and scripting improvements:
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented geometry <code>.from*</code> static constructors for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Implemented partial support for CSS <code>calc()</code> in color keywords.</li>
<li>Implemented Array &#34;find from last&#34; feature (<code>findLast</code> and <code>findLastIndex</code>).</li>
<li>Implemented <code>Object.hasOwn(object,property)</code>.</li>
<li>Implemented several additional Intl API methods and functions. This improves web compatibility with sites making use of things like <code>hourCycle</code>, advanced <code>DateTimeFormat</code>, <code>Intl.Locale</code>, and <code>Intl</code> as a constructor.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Cleaned up some unused code.</li>
<li>Removed support for Mozilla &#34;experiment&#34; type extensions.</li>
<li>Improved the JavaScript garbage collector&#39;s sweeping. This should fix a few intermittent crashes and improve performance.</li>
<li>Implemented some structural changes to the source to make future porting easier, and preparing for switching to C++17.</li>
<li>Removed handling of symlinks for directory linstings to prevent potential security issues by walking symlinks when uploading. This effectively reverts a change made in Firefox 50 where this functionality was introduced. A case of &#34;Not such a good idea after all&#34; ;-)</li>
<li>Updated the list of extensions on Windows treated as &#34;executable&#34;.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-37208.</li>
<li>Made preparations for for requiring Authorization in CORS ACAH preflight.<br/>
Since no browser honors this part of the spec at the moment this is left disabled until there is consensus among browsers.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 2 fixed, 2 rejected, 20 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>57060: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.3.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 12:22:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.2.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.2.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small bugfix and stability update.<br/>
There were no applicable Mozilla security bugs this time around.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a crash in devtools in some OOM situations.</li>
<li>Fixed crashes when internal script execution was blocked by extensions.</li>
<li>Fixed crashes with WebComponents&#39; ::slotted selector.</li>
<li>Disabled incremental cycle collector by default to avoid performance regressions.</li>
<li>Updated the default override for chase.com to work around issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>53407: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.2.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.2.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.2.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is another important, major development update, continuing our rapid development efforts in the v32 milestone.<br/>
With this version we should have restored web compatibility with the majority of reported problematic websites. If you were previously running into websites being problematic in Pale Moon, it may be a good idea to try them again with this release.<br/>
Special thanks to Job Bautista, martok, dbsoft, FranklinDM and Travis for continuing their hard work making this a reality!<br/>
This updates our UXP/Goanna platform version to 6.2.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented dynamic module imports. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented exporting of async functions in modules.</li>
<li>Implemented JavaScript class fields. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented logical assignment operators ||=, &amp;&amp;= and ??=.</li>
<li>Implemented a solution for websites using the officially deprecated ambiguous <code>window.event</code>. This is disabled by default but can be enabled through about:config&#39;s <code>dom.window.event.enabled</code> preference. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented self.structuredClone() (this may be very obscure to anyone except web developers. Apologies ;-) )</li>
<li>Implemented Element.replaceChildren. Once again primarily a web developer note.</li>
<li>Improved Shadow DOM :host matching.</li>
<li>Implemented WebComponents&#39; CSS ::slotted() and related functionality.</li>
<li>Improved page caching in our memory allocator.</li>
<li>Added support for FFmpeg 6.0, especially important for bleeding-edge Linux distros.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential drawing deadlock for images, specifically SVG. This solves a number of hang-on-shutdown scenarios.</li>
<li>Fixed various crashes related to WebComponents and our recent JavaScript work.</li>
<li>Fixed various build-from-source issues on secondary target platforms.</li>
<li>Fixed various small browser front-end scripting issues that could lead to errors or broken functionality.</li>
<li>Fixed handling of async (arrow) functions declared inside constructors.</li>
<li>Fixed various small JavaScript conformance issues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where JavaScript (only in modules) would not properly create async wrappers.</li>
<li>Updated the DOM Performance API to the current spec (User Timing L3).<br/>
See implementation notes, especially if you intend to use this in web content for critical functionality.</li>
<li>Updated keypress event handling to send keypress events on Ctrl+Enter.</li>
<li>Updated internal JavaScript structures to make future porting easier, as well as improve JavaScript performance.</li>
<li>Updated window handling and styling on Mac.</li>
<li>Updated the Freetype lib to 2.13.0.</li>
<li>Updated the Harfbuzz lib to 7.1.0.</li>
<li>Updated our DNS lookup calls to use inet_ntop() instead of the deprecated inet_ntoa().</li>
<li>Updated the Fetch API to use the global&#39;s base URL instead of the entry document&#39;s base URL for spec compliance.</li>
<li>We no longer support the outmoded fontconfig on GTK systems.</li>
<li>We no longer parse or return the body of known-empty responses from servers (content-length of 0, or in case of HEAD or CONNECT methods).</li>
<li>Implemented scaled font caching on GTK, improving performance.</li>
<li>Fixed a build issue when building for Linux on ARM64 on later distros.</li>
<li>Split out more parts of the browser into separate .dll files on Windows to reduce compiler strain and an oversized xul.dll</li>
<li>Removed mozilla::AlignedStorage (code cleanup).</li>
<li>Builds for FreeBSD now use xz for packaging instead of bzip2. By request, we now also offer GTK2 builds for FreeBSD.</li>
<li>Merged the preference dom.getRootNode.enabled into the dom.webcomponents.enabled pref. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential DoS issue with JPEG decoding.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue in Windows widget code that could lead to crashes.</li>
<li>Disabled potentially hazardous external protocols on Windows.</li>
<li>Added known-problematic .dlls to the internal blocklist.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-32209, CVE-2023-32214 and several others that do not have a CVE designation.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 4 fixed, 1 rejected, 27 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>JavaScript modules have various methods of being loaded into web page content. One of the later introduced methods is a function-style import() declaration, so-called &#34;dynamic module imports&#34; that has been used by various web frameworks, causing issues for Pale Moon resulting in blank pages in most cases (since the websites would not actually use document structure HTML, but rather JavaScript to create content, all from imported modules). This has been a major web compatibility issue lately and we&#39;re pleased to announce that this complex bit of machinery has been implemented.</li>
<li>JavaScript&#39;s language specification is continuing to be watered down from a prototyping language towards a more &#34;C-like&#34; hybrid. As part of that effort, JavaScript classes were introduced in ECMAScript 6, and now further expanded in ES2022 with class fields and private class fields/methods, as well as statics. We should have a complete implementation of this now, which constitutes the more important parts of the ES2022 language update.</li>
<li>The use of the outdated Microsoft Internet Explorer global window.event has been a pervasive web compatibility issue for us, especially since it was officially deprecated and we never implemented this ambiguous and unreliable property that is highly-context sensitive. Websites should use the event as passed into the event handler to get the event source instead. However, since neither Chrome nor Firefox have dropped this and seem to be playing a game of &#34;chicken&#34;, it remains in use on the web. To deal with this conflict, we have now implemented the equivalent behind a preference to enable users to (temporarily) use the global window.event while webmasters update their websites. We hope the Google camp will finally drop this one soon so we can be done with this legacy quirk.</li>
<li>The DOM Performance API was updated to the User Timing level 3 spec. It should be critically noted that the DOM Performance API was never designed to be used as a matter of course on published content, and was designed only for page performance analysis use by web designers. Of course, as part of making dev tools available to the web, a lot of abuse ensued because of the accurate navigation and timing measurements that this API can provide (looking at you, Google!). Because of tight integration with web content analysis, the older spec implementation we had was causing issues and actually breaking some services, so we updated it, but with a few important key differences:<br/>
In Pale Moon, we keep navigation timing disabled because it&#39;s a notable privacy issue for the data it can gather (exact navigational events and timings). If you&#39;re a web dev and need these timing measurements, you can enable them with dom.enable_performance_navigation_timing.<br/>
Our implementation, contrary to the spec, does not allow unlimited recording of performance events (effectively logging every page event!) which can also rapidly eat up memory. Instead we enforce a sane default quota that should be roomy enough for all legitimate use, but prevents runaway resource use or extensive logging of user actions.<br/>
If the set quota is reached, a warning will be printed in the console and the recorded performance events will be thrown away. If you (foolishly) rely on Performance API events for your web application to function, be aware this may cause compatibility issues as the API was, again, not designed to be used in such a fashion. For event handling, there are much better alternatives available which do not involve extensive recording of user data or relying on a developer tool API.</li>
<li>We&#39;ve historically implemented the DOM getRootNode function as it was being used in the wild as a standalone function, however its main intent has always been to be a helper function part of Shadow DOM/WebComponents. As such we have now merged the preference into the WebComponents preference, enabling and disabling it along with the rest of our WebComponents implementation.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>49873: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.2.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 09:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.1.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a crash in CompareDocumentPosition with Shadow DOM.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash with display:contents styling.</li>
<li>Added a preference to disable the TLS 1.3 protocol downgrade sentinel (see implementation notes).</li>
<li>Changed the way large clipboard copy/paste operations are handled, improving privacy (see implementation notes).</li>
<li>Improved filename safety when saving files to prevent potential environment leaks (bis).</li>
<li>Improved sanity checks of MIME type headers.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-29545 and CVE-2023-29539.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 2 fixed, 1 rejected, 49 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Some proxies and middleware boxes improperly handle the TLS 1.3 protocol handshake causing an insecure downgrade to TLS 1.2. With our recent update of NSS, Pale Moon no longer allows this kind of protocol downgrade when trying to establish a TLS 1.3 connection to a server. The resulting error is ssl_error_rx_malformed_server_hello with an inability to connect to the server. To enable users to still connect to the servers or devices in question, we&#39;ve added an option to switch off the downgrade sentinel. To switch it off as a temporary workaround, set security.tls.hello_downgrade_check to false.</li>
<li>If copy and paste operations to/from the browser are performed, Pale Moon writes clipboard contents to disk in a temporary cache file if the copy/paste amount is particularly large, to avoid using large amounts of memory to hold this data. The average paste/clipboard size doesn&#39;t tend to hit this limit in which case it is just held in memory.</li>
<li>Previously, these cache files, while in the O.S. temporary file location (%TEMP% or /tmp), would not be consistently cleaned up, potentially causing privacy issues if persisted. This was changed to using auto-cleaning anonymous temp files, improving user privacy and relying less on the O.S. or user performing cleanup of temporary file storage. Thanks to Sandra for pointing this out and providing the patch.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>46153: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 08:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.1.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is another major update with important compatibility improvements for the web. Most notably, our implementation of Google WebComponents is now at a state where we enabled them by default.</p>
<p dir="auto">Additionally, our Mac builds (for both Intel and ARM Macs) are no longer in beta and considered stable. Signed/notarized builds with the regular branding are available from the download page!</p>
<p dir="auto">Huge thanks to FranklinDM for his work this cycle getting us to this point. Of course major thanks to everyone who has contributed to this complex and difficult WebComponents task over a long time!<br/>
Thanks also to Martok and Job Bautista for continuing to work on and improve the JavaScript engine as well as u3shit for working on video playback improvements.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Shadow DOM and CustomElements, collectively making up WebComponents, have been enabled by default which should bring much broader web compatibility to the browser for many a site that uses web 2.0+ frameworks. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Tab titles in the browser now fade if they are too long instead of using ellipses, to provide a little more readable space to page titles. Note that this may require some updates to tab extensions or themes.</li>
<li>A number of site-specific overrides have been updated or removed because they are no longer necessary or current with the platform developments in terms of web compatibility. We could use your help evaluating the ones that are still there. <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/issues/1914" data-markdown-generated-content="" class="ref-issue" rel="nofollow">#1914</a></li>
<li>Updated our promises and async function implementation to the current spec.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>Promise.any()</code></li>
<li>Fixed several crashes related to regular expression code.</li>
<li>Improved regular expression object handling so it can be properly garbage collected.</li>
<li>Fixed some VP8 video playback.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the caret (text cursor) would sometimes not be properly visible.</li>
<li>Updated the embedded emoji font.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>:is()</code> and <code>:where()</code> CSS pseudo-classes.</li>
<li>Implemented complex selectors for the <code>:not()</code> CSS pseudo-class.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>inset</code> CSS shorthand property.</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>env()</code> environment variable CSS function. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented handling for RGB encoded video playback (instead of just YUV).</li>
<li>Implemented handling for full-range videos (0-255 luminance levels) giving better video playback quality.</li>
<li>Removed the WebP image decoder pref. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Enabled the Web text-to-speech API by default (only supported on some operating systems).</li>
<li>Updated NSPR to 4.35 and NSS to 3.79.4</li>
<li>Cleaned up unused &#34;tracking protection&#34; plumbing. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Cleaned up URI Classifier plumbing (Google SafeBrowsing leftover).</li>
<li>Fixed several intermittent and difficult-to-trace crashes.</li>
<li>Improved content type security of <code>jar:</code> channels. DiD</li>
<li>Improved JavaScript JIT code generation safety. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed potential crash scenarios in the graphics subsystem. DiD</li>
<li>Improved filename safety when saving files to prevent potential environment leaks.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-25751, CVE-2023-28163 and several others that do not have a CVE.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 1 fixed, 4 DiD, 14 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Google WebComponents has been long-running major feature work in UXP. We&#39;re finally at a level with this (after several setbacks and brick-walling) that it can be enabled by default. Please note that while this greatly improves web compatibility with many Chrome-focused websites using these controversial technologies, our implementation is not yet complete and more work is necessary. As a result, this change to enable it by default may actually break some previously-working websites as well, but it&#39;s expected the majority will work at our current state of implementation. Please visit the forum if you need help with web compatibility issues.</li>
<li>The <code>env()</code> CSS function was implemented for compatibility with websites that rely on this without fallback. Note that this function actually has no real use for desktops as it is primarily used to indicate environmental restrictions of mobile screens, e.g. extra space needed to avoid a camera notch or folding screen margin. However, due to the way certain sites implement their styling in a mobile-first approach, it is assumed that this function is available on all systems and in all browsers by these sites. Note that Pale Moon simply hard-codes queried values here.</li>
<li>WebP images have had a stable and complete implementation in Pale Moon for a long time now, so the preference to disable support for it has been removed, as it&#39;s considered by now to be one of the &#34;staple&#34; image formats supported by web browsers. This was done to reduce complexity for content negotiation, especially since we&#39;re adding more support for JPEG-XL that still isn&#39;t as-complete. From here on out, we simply always support WebP decoding.</li>
<li>While we&#39;ve had a preference for &#34;tracking protection&#34; in our browser implementation (in <code>about:config</code>), this marketed feature of Firefox was never adopted by us, because it is for the most part a service-based feature, and the non-service parts were undesirable as they were crippling useful APIs. Our effective protection against tracking has not changed, we have simply removed the preference and plumbing for a non-functional service feature that would potentially give the false impression it would do anything.<br/>
As a reminder, if you are concerned about tracking, use a competent adblocker extension, and enable &#34;Tell sites not to share or sell my data&#34; in Preferences -&gt; Privacy under &#34;Data Privacy&#34;. You may also want to enable &#34;canvas poisoning&#34; by setting <code>canvas.poisondata</code> to true in <code>about:config</code> to reduce the risk of fingerprinting through canvases.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>42105: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 15:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32.1.0 beta 3</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_beta3</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">For details see <a href="https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;t=29528&amp;p=237287#p237287" data-markdown-generated-content="" rel="nofollow">https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;t=29528&amp;p=237287#p237287</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>39067: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_beta3</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 14:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32.1.0 beta 2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_beta2</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">Please see <a href="https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;t=29528&amp;p=237282#p237282" data-markdown-generated-content="" rel="nofollow">https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;t=29528&amp;p=237282#p237282</a> for details.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>39066: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_beta2</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 10:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32.1.0 beta 1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_beta1</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">Please see <a href="https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;t=29528" data-markdown-generated-content="" rel="nofollow">https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=5&amp;t=29528</a> for details</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>38849: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.1.0_beta1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 20:29:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a crash in the new regular expression code.</li>
<li>Added <code>{Extended_Pictographic}</code> unicode property escape to regular expressions.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression in regular expressions for literal parsing of invalid ranges.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to pick up fixes.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-25733 (DiD), CVE-2023-25739 (DiD) and CVE-2023-0767.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 1 fixed, 2 DiD, 14 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>37336: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 22:59:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 32.0.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.0.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto"><strong>This is a new milestone release.</strong><br/>
Primary focus for this milestone is web compatibility, in particular Regular Expression extensions, standards compliance issues and further JPEG-XL support.<br/>
This milestone now offers full coverage of the ECMAScript 2016-2020 JavaScript specifications, with the exception of BigInt primitives.<br/>
Special thanks to Martok, Job Bautista and FranklinDM without whom this milestone would not have been possible, and to dbsoft for putting in the effort to work on Mac and FreeBSD builds.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Most important changes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented Regular Expression named capture groups.</li>
<li>Implemented Regular Expression unicode property escapes.</li>
<li>Re-implemented Regular Expression lookaround/lookbehind (without crashing this time ;) ).</li>
<li>Implemented progressive decoding for JPEG-XL.</li>
<li>Implemented animation for JPEG-XL.</li>
<li>Implemented a compatibility mode for  elements. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Renamed CSS offset-* properties to inset-* to align with the latest spec and the web.</li>
<li>Fixed CSS inheritance and padding issues in some cases.</li>
<li>Aligned parsing of incorrectly duplicated HSTS headers with expected behavior (discard all but the first one).</li>
<li>Implemented a method to avoid memory exhaustion in case of (very) large resolution animated images.</li>
<li>Updated the JPEG-XL and Highway libraries to a recent, stable version.</li>
<li>Cleaned up some unused CSS prefixing code.</li>
<li>Improved the ability to link on *nix operating systems with other linkers than gcc&#39;s default.</li>
<li>Stability improvements (potential crash fixes).</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2023-23598, CVE-2023-23599 and several others that do not have a CVE number.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 4 fixed, 2 DiD, 19 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Platform support:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>We&#39;re working on finalizing official builds for Mac OS and FreeBSD. These are currently in beta and can be downloaded from the Contributed Builds page. Please note that you may run into some system compatibility issues with these builds. If you do, please go to the forum and report it in the appropriate board!</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>To provide users with a temporary work-around for non-compliant websites, a compatibility mode for <code>&lt;button&gt;</code> elements was implemented, which will treat <code>&lt;button&gt;</code> elements as generic containers instead of actual form button elements. This has been necessary because Chrome is not standards compliant in this respect and website developers regularly make the mistake of trying to use active content on button faces and expecting pointer events to end up being sent to the active content and not the button (which is <a href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/form-elements.html#the-button-element" rel="nofollow">not what the standard prescribes</a>! See &#34;content model&#34; on the standards page stating there &#34;must be no interactive content descendant&#34;). Webmasters should be alerted to this compliance issue, but it can (temporarily) be worked around in the browser from this point for forward by setting the preference <code>dom.forms.button.standards_compliant</code> to false and restarting the browser. Note that this is a workaround and the only actual solution is advocacy for the standard and more browsers becoming standards compliant.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>33614: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/32.0.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 11:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.4.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed JPEG-XL&#39;s transparency display for images with an alpha channel.</li>
<li>Temporarily removed regex lookbehind to stop crashes occurring on 32-bit builds of the browser.</li>
<li>Added some extra sanity checks to our zip/jar/xpi reader to avoid issues with corrupt archives.</li>
<li>Aligned cookie checks with RFC 6265 bis. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Removed obsolete code in Windows widgets that could cause potential issues with long paths and file names on supported versions.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2022-46876, CVE-2022-46874 and several others that do not have a CVE number.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 4 fixed, 20 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>RFC 6265 has been worked on with draft changes describing how cookies are actually being handled in the real world, in the bis versions of the RFC. While these changes have not yet been finalized, browsers in general do adhere to the latest available bis version of this RFC. Specifically, the long-standing exceptions for cookie names and values have been formalized, e.g. having quoted values. Our behavior has changed in that we now once again accept Tab characters (0x09) which is the one excluded control character from the range that is otherwise forbidden. We also no longer apply these checks exclusively to those in http headers, and any way of setting cookies must now adhere to the valid range. Cookies that fail these range checks for valid characters will be ignored.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>28397: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 09:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon out-of-band release</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">Win32 rebuild only</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>25145: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 14:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.4.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a bugfix release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed wrong color of decoded JPEG-XL images.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with plugins not receiving keypress events properly.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>24653: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.4.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update, adding JPEG-XL image support among other things.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added support for the JPEG-XL image format.</li>
<li>Implemented regular expressions lookaround/lookbehind.</li>
<li>Aligned CORS header parsing with the updated spec. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>We no longer fire keypress events for non-printable keys. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Added support for MacOS 13 &#34;Ventura&#34; in the platform, primarily benefitting White Star.</li>
<li>Fixed potentially problematic thread locking code on *nix platforms.</li>
<li>Fixed some small issues in the display and operation of the Web Developer tools.</li>
<li>Removed unused but performance-impacting panning and tab animation measuring code. (telemetry leftovers)</li>
<li>Improved code for SunOS builds.</li>
<li>Updated Internationalization data for time zones.</li>
<li>Fixed a buffer overflow for Mac builds.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2022-45411 and potential issues without a CVE number.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 2 fixed, 1 DiD, 1 deferred, 25 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>CORS support has been updated to the current spec. Most importantly, Pale Moon now accepts wildcard entries (&#34;*&#34;) for the CORS statements Access-Control-Expose-Headers, Access-Control-Allow-Headers and Access-Control-Allow-Method. Note that wildcards are ignored (according to the spec) when credentials are passed.</li>
<li>Pale Moon will no longer fire the keypress events in content when the key pressed is a non-printable key. This is in response to issues where webmasters would use rudimentary and naïve input-restricting scripts in onkeypress handlers that would not take into account editing keys or navigation keys, causing issues for users trying to enter data into forms (and e.g. finding they could no longer use backspace, cursor keys or tab). This aligns our behavior with other browsers for web compatibility, although it should be considered a website error expecting not all keypresses to be intercepted in keypress events.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>23343: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.4.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 01:12:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale moon 31.3.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.3.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and compatibility update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added detection suport for the newly-released MacOS 13 (Ventura).</li>
<li>Fixed a potential heap Use-After-Free risk in Expat. (CVE-2022-40674) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed potentially undefined behavior in our thread locking code. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable crash in the refresh driver.</li>
<li>Fixed potentially undefined behavior when base-64 decoding. DiD</li>
<li>Implemented a texture size cap for WebGL to prevent potential issues with some graphics drivers. DiD</li>
<li>Updated site-specific overrides to address issues with ZoHo.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 1 fixed, 2 DiD, 6 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>20569: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.3.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.3.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.3.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to back out the changes to handling of flex containers in 31.3.0 since it caused severe usability issues on several websites.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>15488: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.3.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale moon 31.3.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.3.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development, bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented .at(index) JavaScript method on built-in indexables (Array, String, TypedArray).</li>
<li>Implemented the use of EventSource in workers.</li>
<li>Enabled the sending of the Origin: header by default on same-origin requests.</li>
<li>Changed how Pale Moon is built. We are now using Visual Studio 2022 on Windows, and have made build system changes to reduce build times and pressure on the linker on all platforms.</li>
<li>Changed how Pale Moon handles standalone wave audio files (.wav). See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Improved string normalization.</li>
<li>Updated the handling of CSS &#34;supports&#34; to now accept unparenthesized strings (spec update).</li>
<li>Updated the handling of flex containers in web pages for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Fixed various issues when building for Mac OS X.</li>
<li>Fixed various C++ standard conformance issues in the source code.</li>
<li>Fixed several issues building on SunOS and Linux with various configurations and gcc versions.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with regular expressions&#39; dotAll syntax and usage. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Switched custom hash map to std::unordered_map where prudent.</li>
<li>Cleaned up and updated IPC thread locking code.</li>
<li>Removed spacing for accessibility focus rings in form controls to align styling of them with expected metrics.</li>
<li>Removed the unnecessary control module for building with non-standard configurations of the platform.</li>
<li>Removed the -moz prefix from min-content and max-content CSS keywords where it was still in use.</li>
<li>Security fixes: CVE-2022-40956 and CVE-2022-40958.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 2 fixed, 11 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Pale Moon would previously send standalone wave audio files (.wav) to the system-configured media player if they would be opened standalone (i.e. not inside a  HTML element in a page). This was done due to the historical use of rather exotic codecs in .wav files that would not be broadly supported in the browser. In the current day, however, this is much less of a concern. If you prefer to retain the old behavior and send .wav files to whatever the configured system media player is, then you should set the preference media.wave.play-stand-alone to false in about:config.</li>
<li>There was a spec compliance issue with the dotAll regular expression implementation, causing it to not work properly. Specifically, using the new RegExp() constructor would not accept &#34;s&#34; as a flag, and the .dotAll property was not cased properly (all lowercase) causing compatibility issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>15403: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.3.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 07:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.2.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.2.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major bugfix and development update.<br/>
Special thanks to Athenian200, Jobbautista9, Martok and dbsoft for their contributions this cycle :)</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented CSS white-space: break-spaces for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Implemented Intl.RelativeTimeFormat for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Implemented &#34;Origin header CSRF mitigation&#34;. This is still disabled by default to investigate potential issues with CloudFlare-backed sites.</li>
<li>Implemented support for async generator methods in JavaScript.</li>
<li>Added preliminary support for building on Apple Silicon like M1/M2 SoC.</li>
<li>Added support for building with Visual Studio 2022.</li>
<li>Improved the handling of CSS &#34;sticky&#34; elements in tables.</li>
<li>Improved stack size limits on all platforms. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Updated function.toString handling to align with the updated JavaScript spec. This should improve web compatibility.</li>
<li>Updated Unicode support to Unicode v11, and updated the ICU library accordingly. Building without ICU is no longer supported.</li>
<li>Updated many in-tree third-party libraries to pick up various performance and stability improvements.</li>
<li>Updated site-specific user-agent overrides to work around issues with Google fonts, Citi bank (again!) and MeWe.</li>
<li>Removed some leftover (and unused) telemetry code in the platform and front-end.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with VP9 video playback on Windows on some systems.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the add-ons manager not properly handling empty update URLs.</li>
<li>Fixed a major performance regression on *nix based systems due to incorrect thread handling.</li>
<li>Fixed volume handling when building with the sndio audio back-end.</li>
<li>Pale Moon no longer applies content security policies to documents that are explicitly loaded as data documents or to images. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Cleaned up some unnecessary code from the source tree for unused build back-ends, Firefox marketplace &#34;apps&#34;, and the rather ridiculous moz://a protocol handler.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.52.8 to pick up several defense-in-depth security fixes.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 3 DiD, 12 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Prior to this version, Pale Moon would apply Content Security Policies (CSPs) to all requests made to servers that would respond with a policy header, as one would expect for strict use of CSPs as-intended. Unfortunately, Chrome has been less strict in applying these policies and specifically excluded applying these policies to images and &#34;data documents&#34;. As a result, web compatibility became a problem for non-Google browsers with webmasters being oblivious about their overzealous CSPs deployed on websites, causing images (especially SVG) and data to not load or load properly. To align with mainstream browser behavior and improve web compatibility on misconfigured websites, we are now no longer applying CSPs to images or documents explicitly loaded as arbitrary data.</li>
<li>We&#39;ve adjusted default per-thread stack sizes in the platform to be more generous on all platforms. This allows the browser to render more deeply nested visual elements in web pages and the new limit matches the capabilities of mainstream browsers as a result. Please note that some custom builds may need to adjust their linker&#39;s stack sizes on some operating systems to come to a stable and usable build with this change since the new Goanna rendering depth requires this larger stack size to not run out of memory. The default per-thread stack size is now 2 MB with the exception of 32-bit Windows builds where 1.5 MB is used to go easy on its limited address space. Custom Linux builds with system-default small stack sizes should adjust their build configuration accordingly.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>9861: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.2.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 01:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.1.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated the list of blocked external protocol handlers to combat abuse of OS-supplied services on Windows.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with revoked site certificates when connecting through a proxy.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.52.7 to pick up some security fixes.</li>
<li>Updated site-specific user agent overrides to work around bad sniffing practices of dropbox and vimeo.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2022-34478, CVE-2022-34476, CVE-2022-34480 DiD, CVE-2022-34472, CVE-2022-34475 DiD, CVE-2022-34473 DiD, CVE-2022-34481 and a memory safety issue that doesn&#39;t have a CVE number.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 4 fixed, 4 DiD, 2 rejected, 11 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">Rejected patches were for behavioral changes to long-standing drag and drop behavior that were marked as potential security issues. The amount of social engineering and user interaction required to abuse this behavior however has made it not a real practical issue over the past 9 years and the measures required to work around it as Mozilla has now done were considered disproportional in complexity and impact on browser behavior to warrant accepting them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>9851: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 10:22:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale moon 31.1.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.1.0_Release_build2</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update, focusing on media support, browser stability, performance and web compatibility.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added Mojeek as an additional search engine in the browser. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented &#34;nullish coalescing operator&#34; (thanks, FranklinDM!) for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Fixed various crash scenarios in XPCOM.</li>
<li>Fixed an important stability and performance issue related to hardware acceleration.</li>
<li>Fixed a long-standing issue where overly-long address bar tooltips wouldn&#39;t break into multiple lines but instead cut off on the right side.</li>
<li>Fixed a long-standing issue where dynamic datalist updates for <code>&lt;select&gt;</code> and similar elements wouldn&#39;t properly update the option list.</li>
<li>Disabled broken links to MDN articles in developer tools.</li>
<li>Updated media support to include support for libavcodec 59/FFmpeg 5.0 for MP4 playback on Linux (thanks, Travis!)</li>
<li>Enabled the date picker for <code>&lt;input type=date&gt;</code>. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Re-enabled the use of FIPS mode for NSS. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Improved memory handling and memory safety in the JavaScript engine, further reducing current and future crash scenarios.</li>
<li>Improved memory handling in the graphics subsystem of Goanna.</li>
<li>Updated FFvpx to v4.2.7</li>
<li>Slightly reduced strictness of media checking for improved compatibility with questionable &#34;gif&#34; video encoders used on major websites.</li>
<li>Cleaned up the way file pickers (file open/save/save as dialogs) are handled on Windows.</li>
<li>Restored the <code>gMultiProcessBrowser</code> property of the browser for Firefox extension compatibility. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Improved the way data is transferred to and from canvases to prevent memory safety issues.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.52.6 to address security issues.</li>
<li>Reduced blocking severity for some extensions that were marked hard blockers for GRE (but aren&#39;t for UXP).</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2022-31739, CVE-2022-31741, and other security issues that do not have a CVE number.</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 2 fixed, 1 DiD, 26 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation/build notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Following the concerns surrounding bias, censorship and unwanted filtering of search results by almost all available search engines, we&#39;ve contacted Mojeek to have their search engine added by default to Pale Moon. This was done to offer a truly independent search alternative that has its own (long-standing) search index of the Web and does not rely on the major indexers like Bing, Google or Yahoo, who all apply bias and filtering to varying degrees on their search results (e.g. about politics or the war in the Ukraine). Since privacy-focused search engines like DuckDuckGo do rely on search results from these &#34;big indexers&#34;, whatever their &#34;upstream&#34; decides to be filtered out will also affect your results through those search engines. Mojeek offers its own, entirely independent search results which may provide you with truly independent alternative results. Give it a try!</li>
<li>Form input fields of type &#34;date&#34; will now pop up a graphical calendar to pick dates instead of having to manually enter the dates. Please note that the default format will match the base language of the browser (American English) which will be reflected in the <code>mm/dd/yyyy</code> placeholder. This is cosmetic only and does not actually influence how the date is passed to the server via the form. More work is needed for better localization of date and time input fields but that did not make this release.</li>
<li>FIPS mode is a special (rather archaic) operating mode of the NSS security library and software security device that handles certificates and credentials in the browser. In v31.0.0 this operating mode was no longer supported which resulted in some users who had previously enabled FIPS mode in the browser from accessing their credentials (giving errors on the master password, instead). For the time being, support for this mode is enabled again but if you use it, please disable this mode as it will go away. Standard operating mode with a master password is more secure than FIPS mode at this point, and FIPS was only ever necessary for US governmental use and &#34;grandfathered in&#34; without getting much attention. This will go away permanently over time so please pre-empt this removal by disabling FIPS mode if you had enabled it (its control can be found in Preferences -&gt; Advanced -&gt; Certificates tab -&gt; Button &#34;Security devices&#34; -- yes, it&#39;s buried pretty deep ;-) ).</li>
<li>Windows binaries are now being built and linked against a newer Windows SDK (10.0.22000.0) to align with system support for Windows 11. It is unlikely that this will negatively affect any users at this point in time.</li>
<li>While we don&#39;t support multi-process browsing or &#34;electrolysis&#34;, extensions may still be checking what Firefox used as an indicator to know if electrolysis was enabled in it, which in some cases would require the extension to adjust its behavior. To provide better compatibility with legacy extensions that might otherwise error out when the <code>gMultiprocessBrowser</code> property was completely undefined, we restored this property (hard-coded to &#34;false&#34; since we don&#39;t support multi-process).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>9847: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.1.0_Release_build2</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 12:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale moon 31.1.0 Release candidate</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.1.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">Do not use this tagged version.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>9844: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.1.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 31.0.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.0.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">New milestone release. for details see <a href="http://www.palemoon.org/releasenotes.shtml" rel="nofollow">official release notes</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>9841: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/31.0.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 08:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>v29.4.6</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.4.6_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and bugfix release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a potential crash issue on bing.com.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.52.4 to address security issues.</li>
<li>Fixed some thread locking issues. DiD</li>
<li>Worked around a Mesa driver bug that could cause crashes.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential resource access issue in devtools. DiD</li>
<li>Security issues with CVEs addressed: CVE-2022-1097, CVE-2022-28285 (DiD) and CVE-2022-28283 (DiD).</li>
<li>UXP Mozilla security patch summary: 1 fixed, 5 DiD, 2 rejected, 23 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>9834: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.4.6_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 12:33:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.4.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.4.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security release. Our release schedule was adjusted here to provide web compatibility improvements and not just a security update this month.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented promise.allSettled().</li>
<li>Implemented global origin on windows and workers.</li>
<li>Improved performance of memory allocations.</li>
<li>Updated libcubeb to the current development version.</li>
<li>This improves OSS compatibility and addresses potential crashes, performance issues and security issues.</li>
<li>Updated SQLite to 3.36.0.</li>
<li>Improved thread safety of the web content cache. DiD</li>
<li>Added several fixes to avoid potential crashes and security issues. DiD</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 5 DiD, 12 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210817" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - August 17, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Ghost</author>
      <guid>7484: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.4.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 11:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.3.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.3.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>&#34;Web Developer&#34; is now called &#34;Developer Tools&#34; in the menus.</li>
<li>Updated and aligned about:home, the QuickDial page and logopage styling.</li>
<li>Re-organized the privacy category in the preferences window.</li>
<li>Enabled brotli compression for http for sites that support it. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>EventTarget</code> as a constructor.</li>
<li>Updated Windows 10 toolkit styling.</li>
<li>Updated the port blacklist (removed 10080). See implementation notes.</li>
<li>CSS: Implemented <code>calc()</code> and animation support for <code>stroke-dashoffset</code>.</li>
<li>Added support for checking boolean preferences to chrome CSS style sheets, to support more advanced theming options.</li>
<li>Added support for dynamic dark color capable themes in CSS.</li>
<li>Updated <code>ResizeObserver</code> implementation to a more recent specification. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Removed a metric ton of Macintosh code.</li>
<li>Removed obsolete system theme support from the layout engine.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes.</li>
<li>Linux: blocked particularly old versions of Mesa/Nouveau drivers due to issues.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: <code>CVE-2021-30547</code> and several other issues that don&#39;t have a CVE number.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 3 fixed, 3 DiD, 2 deferred (DiD), 12 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Brotli compression (introduced a few years back) has originally been restricted to https only in web browsers because there was some concern about interaction with middleware boxes with poor design trying to transparently recompress data not recognizing the new compression stream type and causing failures. The kind of processing done in those boxes (SDCH) has long since been deprecated. Since then, the segregation for Brotli between http and https has been maintained by Chrome and Firefox as a vessel to further promote https over http by artificially keeping http less efficient (denying the use of the more dense Brotli compression). Since there is no technical reason not to enable Brotli over http, we will accept (by way of Accept-encoding) Brotli over plain http from this version on, offering up to 20% less bandwidth use when servers also support it.</li>
<li>We maintain a blacklist of ports that should not be addressed from a browser (primarily to prevent scripted abuse). Not too long ago we updated these ports with a number of additional (higher range) ones, including port 10080 (Amanda). Unfortunately there is too much overlap with other common services/devices that also use this (arbitrarily chosen) port, so we&#39;ve removed this particular port again from our blacklist.</li>
<li>The <code>ResizeObserver</code> implementation was changed to now support the updated specification for this API, including the experimental properties <code>contentBoxSize</code> and <code>borderBoxSize</code> which allows finer control to respond to size changes of elements. The old spec sizing property of <code>contentRect</code> remains supported for web compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210719" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - July 19, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Ghost</author>
      <guid>7474: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.3.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 16:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.2.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.2.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small bugfix release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Worked around an issue with autocomplete popups sometimes failing to work (and added some debug console logging to it in case it happens to help find the root cause)</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with DOM mouse scrolling throwing errors.</li>
<li>Fixed a race with network detection routines firing incorrectly when resuming from standby.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when using large uploads through DOM.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the menulist-button on editable menulist widgets was not visible on GTK3.</li>
<li>Reduced the number of reported &#34;important preferences&#34; in troubleshooting information, excluding individual printer details.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the JS JIT compiler not tracing debugger environments (DiD).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">There were no security issues that applied to UXP or Pale Moon this release cycle.</p>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210608" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - June 8, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>7465: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.2.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.2.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.2.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development and bugfix release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Starting with this version, we will no longer be supporting unmaintained legacy Firefox extensions that are not updated for/targeting Pale Moon directly.</strong><br/>
Please see <a href="https://forum.palemoon.org/viewtopic.php?f=1&amp;t=26657" rel="nofollow">this forum post</a> for details.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>When opening tabs from the History side bar, Pale Moon will now warn you about the action if it would result in opening many tabs at once.</li>
<li>Pale Moon now offers &#34;Open All in Tabs&#34; on bookmark folders even if there is only one sub-item in it, for UI consistency.</li>
<li>Added media format controls in the Content category of Preferences.</li>
<li>Added controls for preferred color scheme. <em>See implementation notes.</em></li>
<li>Updated several site-specific user-agent overrides for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Removed the ability to accept Firefox IDs for extension installation.</li>
<li>Removed conditional Macintosh code from the application front-end.</li>
<li>Updated the AV1 reference library to 2.0.</li>
<li>Cleaned up more Android code from the platform.</li>
<li>Updated the embedded emoji font to cater to even more race-dependent profession emoji.</li>
<li>Fixed an overflow in clip paths, potentially causing them to be rendered incorrectly.</li>
<li>Added CSS values <code>smooth</code>, <code>high-quality</code> and <code>pixelated</code> to the <code>image-rendering</code> keyword.</li>
<li>Implemented <code>Intl.NumberFormat.formatToParts()</code> to allow deconstruction of localized number formats by scripts.</li>
<li>Reinstated the <code>dom.details_element.enabled</code> preference and fixed a rendering issue with summary/details html elements.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with CSP <code>.nonce</code> attributes on elements.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2021-29946 <em>DiD</em> and CVE-2021-23994 <em>DiD</em>.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 2 DiD, 14 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>This version adds support for the <code>prefers-color-scheme</code> CSS keyword. This keyword is a media query keyword that indicates to websites whether your content styling preference is &#34;light&#34; or &#34;dark&#34;. Unlike other browsers where this will be tied to your system color scheme and determined automatically (which might be a point on which you can be fingerprinted, so this would be a privacy concern), we&#39;ve decided to give the user control through <em>Preferences -&gt; Content -&gt; Colors</em> where you will find a new control to indicate your user preference (it defaults to &#34;light&#34; for everyone). While this control also gives you the option to disable this feature and effectively not support the keyword, be aware that this might cause issues on some websites that do not provide styling for &#34;unspecified&#34; color scheme preferences.<br/>
In the future we <em>may</em> add an &#34;automatic&#34; option similar to other browsers in case you regularly switch your system application style from light to dark and v.v.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210427" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - April 27, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>7409: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.2.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 10:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.1.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor security and bugfix update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated NSS to fix certificate import and keygen regressions.</li>
<li>Removed restrictions for units of width/height attributes on SVG elements.</li>
<li>Enabled scrollbar-width CSS keyword by default.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2021-23981 and a DiD fix for potential document parser confusion.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 2 DiD, 9 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210330" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - March 30, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>7394: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 08:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.1.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.1.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New features:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Language packs for the following newly-supported languages:
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Arabic (ar)</li>
<li>Chinese Traditional (zh-TW)</li>
<li>Croatian (hr)</li>
<li>Danish (da)</li>
<li>Finnish (fi)</li>
<li>Galician (gl)</li>
<li>Indonesian (id)</li>
<li>Icelandic (is)</li>
<li>Japanese (ja)</li>
<li>Romanian (ro)</li>
<li>Serbian (cyrillic) (sr)</li>
<li>Slovenian (sl)</li>
<li>Thai (th)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Implemented <code>String.prototype.replaceAll()</code>.</li>
<li>Implemented JSON superset proposal.</li>
<li>Implemented well-formed JSON stringify.</li>
<li>Implemented numeric separators in JavaScript.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated timezone data to 2021a.</li>
<li>Updated the wording and inclusion of more select license blocks in about:license.</li>
<li>Updated some site-specific user-agent overrides for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Updated the lz4 library for performance and security updates.</li>
<li>Improved performance of JSON stringify.</li>
<li>Further improved support for building on FreeBSD.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression where changes to useragent compatibility required a restart to take effect.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression where AES-GCM in WebCrypto (&#34;subtle&#34; crypto API) wasn&#39;t working.</li>
<li>This could make certain login procedures fail to work.</li>
<li>Fixed a full browser deadlock when page scripting would flood browsing history with rapid location state changes.</li>
<li>Disabled AV1 codec use by default again since our implementation has significant streaming issues (particularly audio) that needs further work.</li>
<li>Added required interaction with file/folder open dialog boxes on html file input elements on some operating systems to avoid malicious content tricking users into uploading sensitive files unintentionally (related to CVE-2021-23956).</li>
<li>Added a font sanity check to avoid triggering a potential vulnerability on unpatched Windows operating systems (related to CVE-2021-24093).</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2021-23974, CVE-2021-23973 and several memory safety hazards that don&#39;t have CVE numbers.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 4 fixed, 2 DiD, 19 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210302" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - March 2, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>5609: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.1.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 10:06:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and stability update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a browser crash when manipulating frame trees.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with depth textures in ANGLE.</li>
<li>Updated the SSOAU for YouTube Studio.</li>
<li>Security issue addressed: ZDI-CAN-12197.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210205" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - February 5, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Ghost</author>
      <guid>5507: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 18:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 29.0.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.0.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">A new year, a new milestone!</p>
<p dir="auto">While our initial intent was to have Google WebComponent support with this milestone, any reasonable deadline has passed for it.</p>
<p dir="auto">Instead, this new release continues to build on further improvements and enhancements in the platform and additions to the browser, as well as a large number of bugfixes.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New additions:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented <code>Intl.PluralRules</code> API for JavaScript.</li>
<li>Added a frequently-requested preference (<code>browser.tabs.allowTabDetach</code>) to disable &#34;tearing off&#34; of tabs (meaning dragging them outside of the tab bar resulting in them being made into their own window).</li>
<li>Added FLAC as a recognized filetype-by-extension.</li>
<li>Implemented basic support for the <code>scrollbar-width</code> CSS keyword. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Added preliminary support for modern FreeBSD builds.</li>
<li>Selectively enabled core features of the DOM Animations API.</li>
<li>Enabled AV1 video support by default (previously built but not enabled in releases).</li>
<li>Added support for pointer events.</li>
<li>Added support for the SVG transform-box property.</li>
<li>Added support for the inputmode property for forms to enable context-sensitive display of soft keyboards.</li>
<li>Enabled shutting down of the file I/O worker when idle for a while (resource optimization).</li>
<li>Enabled blocking of auto-play of media in the background by default.</li>
<li>We now offer official GTK3 builds for Linux alongside the GTK2 builds.</li>
<li>Partial (and as of yet, not acceptably functional) implementation of Google WebComponents. See implementation notes.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated NSPR to 4.29.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.59.</li>
<li>Disabled legacy database format for storage of certificates and passwords. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Updated several site-specific user-agent overrides for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Improved styling of the &#34;find in page&#34; bar to avoid unreadable text on some system themes.</li>
<li>Removed a large chunk of Android-specific code.</li>
<li>Split gkmedias.dll back out from xul.dll.</li>
<li>Cleaned up a number of redundant and obsolete code paths.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression with the Performance API.</li>
<li>Fixed an initialization issue in the browser when users would force-disable certain types of caching.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when attempting to save a file from FTP that could be displayed in the browser.</li>
<li>Fixed the root cause of an issue with JavaScript module loading causing crashes. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Fixed a rare initialization issue for the print preview window causing it to not display.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash on Mac when text input was not secure.</li>
<li>Disabled the Storage Manager API by default.</li>
<li>Disabled the <code>&lt;menuitem&gt;</code> html tag by default. If you still need this, you can re-enable it with the preference <code>dom.menuitem.enabled</code> in about:config.</li>
<li>Fixed a memory safety issue related to XUL trees (CVE-2021-23962).</li>
<li>Implemented several defense-in-depth measures to improve stability and future security.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 1 fixed, 6 DiD, 1 already implemented, 1 deferred to the next release, 24 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>We&#39;ve implemented basic support for the scrollbar-width CSS keyword. The most important setting used with increasing frequency on the web is scrollbar-width: none effectively disabling scrollbars while not affecting overflow behavior when content would overflow its designated space (normally that would result in scrollbars being added to access the hidden content). This support for none is complete. A different setting for this keyword is thin. While this is implemented, it is currently reliant on the underlying system theme for widgets on various operating systems and (especially on Linux) may have little or no effect depending on the widget theme you are using, resulting in standard-sized scrollbars (the same as auto, the default for this keyword).</li>
<li>The legacy database format for storing security certificates and passwords (dbm, a Berkeley-derived format) is no longer built and as a result the browser will no longer be able to convert the old format (cert8.db and key3.db) to the current format which is SQL-based. Please see our <a href="https://developer.palemoon.org/docs/profile-migration/" rel="nofollow">document on profile migration</a> for pointers on upgrading very old profiles that have not had this migration occur yet.</li>
<li>We tracked down (thanks, jarman!) the issue that had us forced to disable the inlining of code optimization in our JIT compiler for JavaScript (IonMonkey) in our previous version by default, to prevent crashes with module scripts (see release notes of 28.17.0). As a result we&#39;ve been able to reclaim our temporary loss in performance of the browser while solving the crashes caused by this optimization.</li>
<li>We&#39;ve implemented a good chunk of Google WebComponents (CustomElements and Shadow DOM). The incomplete code is behind a preference (<code>dom.webcomponents.enabled</code>) and it is strongly suggested you do not touch it unless you plan on helping us implement the remainder of this fundamentally-web-altering spec. Please do not expect that this preference is a magic wand to make Google and it&#39;s puppy sites suddenly work in &#34;modern&#34; (mind the quotes) ways or without help (e.g. polyfills). While we&#39;ve ticked a lot of the boxes already for a working implementation, this specification is kind of special in that it is all-or-nothing because it is not an extension or evolution of existing technology, but rather an attempt at redefining how websites work and are structured (with plenty of critical feedback because of that) at the most fundamental level.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20210202" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - February 2, 2021</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Ghost</author>
      <guid>5504: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/29.0.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 13:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.17.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.17.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed the way dates and times are formatted in the UI to properly adhere to the user&#39;s regional settings in the O.S.</li>
<li>Re-enabled the DOM Filesystem API for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Moved the global user-agent override to the networking component. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Worked around crashes and run-time issues with module scripts. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Fixed a website layout issue with table-styled elements potentially overlapping when placed inside a flexbox.</li>
<li>Fixed some code logic issues with websockets.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression when waking the computer from standby causing high CPU usage in some uncommon situations.</li>
<li>Updated the list of prohibited ports the browser can use. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Updated root certificates.</li>
<li>Windows: Changed the way downloaded files without an extension are handled. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Mac-beta: Improved version detection of MacOS including Big Sur.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2020-26978 and CVE-2020-35112.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 2 fixed, 1 deferred to the next release, 16 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>The global user-agent override was moved to the networking component where it is actually implemented. The new preference name is <code>network.http.useragent.global_override</code>. Please note that using a blanket override is normally (very) counterproductive and does not, in fact, help much with privacy. It would also override the compatibility modes (Native/Gecko/Firefox) in Pale Moon. As such, the browser will now warn you if the user-agent is globally overridden (in preferences) and allow you to easily reset that override and re-enable the various compatibility modes.</li>
<li>Module scripting caused some persistent and very hard to track browser crashes that we&#39;ve narrowed down to a specific optimization in the JavaScript JIT (Just-In-Time) compiler (IonMonkey). This optimization is now disabled by default but if you need that little extra performance (usually only noticed in very optimized code or some benchmarks) then you can re-enable it, trading in stability, by setting the new preference <code>javascript.options.ion.inlining</code> to <code>true</code>.</li>
<li>Prohibited ports: Pale Moon maintains a blacklist of ports the browser may normally not connect to on servers, to mitigate abusive web scripting employing your browser as an attack bot on servers (e.g. by connecting to mail servers or what not), <a href="https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/new-slipstream-nat-bypass-attacks-to-be-blocked-by-browsers/" rel="nofollow">NAT slipstreaming</a>, and similar security issues. To more thoroughly prevent known abusable ports on servers, this list was extended with a number of additional default ports for various non-http protocols.</li>
<li>Downloaded files without a file extension: When a file without an extension is downloaded, we will now open the download folder where you may choose to take any specific action manually, instead of trying to execute it as a program or through an associated program.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20201218" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - December 18, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Ghost</author>
      <guid>5467: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.17.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 14:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.16.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.16.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development and security update to the browser.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Note for Linux users:</strong> With CentOS 6 going end-of-life, this version will be the last for which we will be building 32-bit Linux official binaries to download. While your distribution may choose to continue offering 32-bit versions of the browser, built from source by the maintainers, we won&#39;t be offering any further official 32-bit Linux binaries on our website. Please check with your distribution&#39;s package maintainers to know if further 32-bit support will be available on your particular flavor of Linux.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Aligned CSS <code>tab-size</code> with the specification and un-prefixed it.</li>
<li>Updated Brotli library to 1.0.9.</li>
<li>Updated JAR lib code.</li>
<li>Optimized UI code, resulting in smaller downloads and less space consumed on disk.</li>
<li>Changed the default Firefox Compatibility version number to 68.0 (since versions ending in .9 makes some frameworks unhappy, refusing access to users)</li>
<li>Cleaned up HPKP leftovers.</li>
<li>Disabled the DOM filesystem API by default.</li>
<li>Removed Phone Vibrator API.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where the software uninstaller would not remove the program files it should.</li>
<li>Fixed a devtools crash related to timeline snapshots.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in Skia that could cause unsafe memory access. [DiD]</li>
<li>Fixed several data race conditions. [DiD]</li>
<li>Fixed an XSS vulnerability where scripts could be executed when pasting data into on-line editors.</li>
<li>Linux: Fixed an overflow issue in freetype.</li>
<li>Security issues addressed: CVE-2020-26960, CVE-2020-26951, CVE-2020-26956, CVE-2020-15999 and several others that do not have a CVE designation.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 4 fixed, 4 defense-in-depth, 3 rejected, 20 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Windows binaries should all be properly code-signed again.</li>
<li>The uninstaller issue might only appear if you have not used the internal updater to update the browser after installation.</li>
<li>The DOM Filesystem and dir picker APIs are, in practice, not used on websites. We&#39;ve disabled these web-exposed APIs because they are not entirely without potential risk, and intend to remove them in a future version unless there is a demonstrable need to keep them as optional (unsupported) APIs in the platform.</li>
<li>One of the rejected security patches deals with entering a single word in the address bar. Standard browser behavior in that situation is for browsers to do a normal network lookup of that word in case it is a LAN machine name (other browsers also do this) which may &#34;leak&#34; your entered search term to the LAN. If you want to avoid this, please <strong>always use the search box for entering web searches</strong>, as it&#39;s unambiguous what to do with single words in that case.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20201124" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - November 24, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Ghost</author>
      <guid>3688: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.16.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 22:43:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.15.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.15.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a standard development and bugfix release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented support for CSS <code>caret-color</code>.</li>
<li>Implemented support for un-prefixed <code>::selection</code> CSS pseudo-element styling.</li>
<li>Fixed another potential crashing scenario in <code>ResizeObservers</code>.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes in the DOM <code>Fetch</code> API.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in table pagination.</li>
<li>Security issues fixed: CVE-2020-15680 (VG-VD-20-115) and several memory safety hazards.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 1 fixed, 2 defense-in-depth, 12 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20201024" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - October 24, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>3644: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.15.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 08:40:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.14.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.14.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This update fixes a few important issues.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed some additional crashes caused by the ResizeObserver API. This should take care of all crashes that have been attributed to this new code.</li>
<li>Fixed erroneous parsing of CSS percentages as number values.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2015: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.14.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.14.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.14.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This update addresses an intermittent crash in the newly-implemented <code>ResizeObserver</code> API (introduced in 28.14.0) occurring on a number of high-profile and often-used websites.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2016: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.14.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 05:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.14.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.14.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development and security update.</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated the browser identity code for website security to more clearly indicate website status.<br/>
A detailed explanation is available on the forum and beyond the scope of these release notes.</li>
<li>Updated unofficial branding to be more generic and more clearly separate unofficial builds from Pale Moon as a product.<br/>
<em>Please note that this goes hand in hand with an update of our redistribution license, and from this point forward any &#34;New Moon&#34; products are to be considered separate, and not unofficial Pale Moon builds or in any way related to or affiliated with Pale Moon, despite the similarity in name.</em></li>
<li>Added a preference (<code>signon.startup.prompt</code>) to give users the option to ask for the Master Password the moment the application starts (before the main window opens). This allows a workaround for getting multiple Master Password prompts if individual components need access to the password store at the same time.</li>
<li>Changed the way download sources are displayed to always use the actual domain downloads are from. In some situations the browser would previously display the domain of the referring page in an inconsistent fashion.</li>
<li>Implemented the ES2019 <code>Object.fromEntries()</code> utility function.</li>
<li>Implemented the CSS <code>flow-root</code> keyword.</li>
<li>(Re-)implemented percentage-based CSS opacity values according to the updated spec.</li>
<li>Implemented the last few missing bits for a standards-compliant implementation of JavaScript modules.(preloading, resource: scheme, etc.)</li>
<li>Implemented the <code>ResizeObserver</code> DOM API.</li>
<li>Fixed a null crash on some websites using CSS clip paths.</li>
<li>Updated script handling inside SVGs to only run scripts if they are enabled and permitted, avoiding a potential XSS pitfall.</li>
<li>Fixed several memory safety hazards and crashes.</li>
<li>Updated the MediaQueryList interface to the updated spec. It now inherits from <code>EventTarget</code> and implements <code>AddEventListener</code>/<code>RemoveEventListener</code> in addition to <code>AddListener</code>/<code>RemoveListener</code> and should improve web compatibility for some sites.</li>
<li>Removed support for the archaic and non-standard <code>&lt;marquee&gt;</code> element.</li>
<li>Removed some leftovers from the discontinued plugin update checker service.</li>
<li>Removed some internal HPKP implementation leftovers.</li>
<li>Cleaned up the Windows widget code to reduce potentially vulnerable direct-dll loads.</li>
<li>Security issues fixed: CVE-2020-15676 and CVE-2020-15677</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 2 fixed, 1 defense-in-depth, 7 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200929" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - September 29, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2017: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.14.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 08:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.13.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.13.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a compatibility, bugfix and security update. Special thanks to our new code contributors this cycle (you know who you are)!</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated the included site-specific user-agent overrides for a number of websites that need them.<br/>
Rewritten the browser&#39;s padlock code to use more modern APIs and provide more accurate security status indication.</li>
<li>Now also with localized tooltips!</li>
<li>Fixed a missing close button on the undo prompt after removing a thumbnail from the QuickDial new tab page.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the alternative stylesheet menu in the browser&#39;s UI not working.</li>
<li>Implemented the use of intrinsic aspect ratios for images to improve layout during load and page positioning.</li>
<li>Added a preference to the use of node.getRootNode and disabled by default. See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Added CSS -webkit-appearance as an alias for -moz-appearance to improve compatibility with websites that only try to use Chrome-specific keywords to style standard form elements.</li>
<li>Updated the SQLite library to 3.33.0.</li>
<li>Reinstated precise floating point precision model in JavaScript for those alternate builders who foolishly try to use the inaccurate &#34;fast&#34; model.</li>
<li>Improved spec compliance of modular JavaScript use (ECMAScript modules).</li>
<li>Changed media errors to be a more generic response, and added a preference (media.sourceErrorDetails.enabled) to enable detailed error reporting of media errors for debugging purposes.<br/>
Previously, detailed errors were provided by default which could lead to privacy issues.</li>
<li>Improved code stability of the AbortController implementation.</li>
<li>Fixed a race condition in the secure connection library (NSS).</li>
<li>Security issues fixed: CVE-2020-15664, CVE-2020-15666, CVE-2020-15667, CVE-2020-15668 and CVE-2020-15669.</li>
<li><em>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 4 fixed, 1 defense-in-depth, 1 rejected, 9 not applicable.</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Implementation notes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>
<p dir="auto">In 28.11.0 we introduced node.getRootNode because some websites would fail with an error if this function was not present. Unfortunately, this caused problems with other sites that (incorrectly) assume Google WebComponents are available when this utility function is present (feature detection gone wrong). While it is considered by some to be part of the Google WebComponents implementation, it actually has utility value outside of that use. Because of the problems caused, we&#39;ve added a preference and disabled it by default, fixing these kinds of websites.</p>
<p dir="auto">When needed, you can re-enable this function with dom.getRootNode.enabled</p>
<p dir="auto">This should improve web compatibility by default yet still allow users to enable this function for websites that use its utility but do not use WebComponents.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200901" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - September 1, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2018: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.13.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 14:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.12.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.12.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added controls for WASM to the browser&#39;s preferences, and enabled by default.</li>
<li>Enabled various arbitrarily-disabled CSS functions.</li>
<li>Added the use of basic path descriptors (i.e. polygon) to css clip paths.</li>
<li>Implemented multithreaded request signal handling for the Abort API. Please see implementation notes below.</li>
<li>Updated the included US-English dictionary, adding approximately 2500 additional words.</li>
<li>Removed the DOM battery API. This was already disabled for privacy reasons for a long while.</li>
<li>Fixed an erroneous warning displayed on toolkit-only add-ons like supplied dictionaries.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the sessionstore tab load preference.</li>
<li>Improved the generation of the names of downloaded files to prevent confusion. (CVE-2020-15658)</li>
<li>Fixed a code issue with base64 encoding of data.</li>
<li>Fixed 2 safety hazards in JavaScript. (One being CVE-2020-15656) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a spec compliance issue with regards to the cross-origin loading of scripts. (CVE-2020-15652)</li>
<li>Improved the loading of a system DLL on Windows, preventing low-risk hijacking potential. (CVE-2020-15657) See implementation notes.</li>
<li>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 4 fixed, 2 defense-in-depth, 15 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">Implementation notes:</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>In 28.11.0, we introduced the Abort API as new code. The implementation of it still had an issue where especially web workers would not always see the availability of abort signals on fetch requests while AbortSignal was implemented in the browser. This effectively made some websites (especially those using a particular polyfill for the Abort API that would detect the need to polyfill by way of Request.signal) throw errors that were fine before. We offered users a workaround by temporarily disabling the AbortController in the browser by way of a preference (dom.abortController.enabled).<br/>
v28.12.0 fixes the multi-threaded handling of signals, which should solve these problems. As such, the workaround is no longer needed and upon upgrade the preference will be reset to enable AbortControllers again.</li>
<li>DLL-hijacking on Windows would only be possible if a malicious actor already either gained administrative access to the program&#39;s installation folder or otherwise have unrestricted access to the program folder (by having it installed in local application folders inside the user&#39;s profile space or other insecure program locations). In that case the system is already compromised and any executable can be replaced, so having dll loading hijacked would be the least of your concerns (i.e. the main program .exe could also be replaced/infected in that case).</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200730" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - July 30, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2019: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.12.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.11.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.11.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed storage format for certificates and passwords to SQLite.</li>
<li>Added a preference (browser.tabs.insertAllAfterCurrent) to enable always adding new tabs after the current tab, whether related or not.</li>
<li>Changed the way Firefox extensions are displayed in the add-on manager (provide a clear warning).</li>
<li>Denied other types of add-ons that aren&#39;t explicitly targeting Pale Moon&#39;s ID.</li>
<li>Improved the browser&#39;s DPI-awareness to be per-monitor instead of system-wide, on supported Windows operating systems.</li>
<li>Updated bookmark backups code with the other half of what should have been done way back when, so they work fully as-intended.</li>
<li>Added a preference (browser.bookmarks.editDialog.showForNewBookmarks) to enable immediately showing the edit dialog for new bookmarks.<br/>
If set to true, clicking the star in the address bar will pop open the edit dialog immediately for changing details/sorting.</li>
<li>Fixed the useragent string in native mode, and updated UA code to properly respond to live changes to some preferences.</li>
<li>Tidied up front-end browser JavaScript.</li>
<li>Changed the way sources are compiled (on-going de-unification).</li>
<li>Improved compatibility with gcc v10</li>
<li>Removed support for the obsolete and unmaintained NVidia 3DVision stereoscopic interface.</li>
<li>Fixed some build issues in non-standard configurations.</li>
<li>Fixed wrong positions when calculating the position for position:absolute child inside a table.</li>
<li>Aligned file name extension of saved url files with other applications (lower case)</li>
<li>Fixed building with --disable-webspeech (to disable speech synthesis)</li>
<li>Added global menubar support for GTK.</li>
<li>Implemented node.getRootNode</li>
<li>Implemented AbortController (Abort API)</li>
<li>Improved the uninstaller to use elevation when prudent and actually remove program files.</li>
<li>Fixed a rare issue with editable page content.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash related to ES module scripts.</li>
<li>Aligned ES module scripting better with the current spec and removed eager instantiation.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with the JPEG encoder. (CVE-2020-12422) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with AppCache manifests. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential crash in JavaScript date parsing.</li>
<li>Fixed a problem with RSA key generation that would make it potentially vulnerable to side-channel attacks. (CVE-2020-12402)</li>
<li>Fixed a potential crash due to multithread race condition. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a correctness issue in URL handling. (CVE-2020-12418) DiD</li>
<li>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 2 fixed, 4 defense-in-depth, 10 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200712" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - July 12, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2020: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.11.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 07:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.10.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.10.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development, bugfix and security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented URLSearchParams&#39; sort() function</li>
<li>Implemented ES2020 globalThis for web compatibility</li>
<li>Improved our WebM media parser to be more tolerant to different encoding styles.</li>
<li>Improved our MP3 media parser to be more tolerant to different encoding styles and particularly tiny files/stream chunks.</li>
<li>Improved performance of table drawing for more corner cases</li>
<li>Changed the way images without a src are handled in page layouts to align with the Chrome-pushed spec.</li>
<li>Added modern MIPS support</li>
<li>Split out the ICU data file from xul.dll on Windows</li>
<li>Fixed a regression in WebAudio channel handling due to a landed security fix.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression preventing scripting from properly disabling input controls</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with border radius sometimes not being honored in tables</li>
<li>Fixed some build issues in non-standard configurations.</li>
<li>Removed more telemetry code</li>
<li>Removed the in-browser speech recognition engine and API</li>
<li>Removed support for the obsolete and unmaintained NVidia 3DVision stereoscopic interface.</li>
<li>Changed handling of braille blanks in the ui (CVE-2020-12409) DiD</li>
<li>Mitigated a potential timing attack against DSA keys in NSS (CVE-2020-12399)</li>
<li>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 1 fixed, 1 defense-in-depth, 8 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200603" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - June 3, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2021: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.10.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 19:44:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.9.3</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.3_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security update.</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a potential vulnerability in the zip file reader. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential vulnerability in the JavaScript JIT compiler related to aliases. DiD</li>
<li>Ported several upstream devtools fixes (addresses CVE-2020-12392 and CVE-2020-12393).</li>
<li>Improved memory safety of some WebAudio calls.</li>
<li>Improved memory safety in the XUL window destructor. DiD</li>
<li>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 3 fixed, 3 Defense-in-depth, 16 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200506" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - May 6, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2022: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.3_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 09:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.9.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor update for stability and compatibility.</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Re-based the 28.9 version of browsers on a separate development branch that excludes the extensive work being done for Google WebComponents, to avoid potential performance and stability issues caused by as-of-yet incomplete and in-progress code for the new milestone.</li>
<li>Enabled DOM High Resolution timestamps for compatibility with websites that strictly rely on them for operation.</li>
<li>Added a preference to allow copying the unescaped URL from the address bar (especially useful for internationalized domain names and paths).<br/>
To enable this, set <code>browser.urlbar.decodeURLsOnCopy</code> to <code>true</code> in about:config</li>
<li>Fixed several application crashes (thanks, Fysac!)</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200427" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - April 27, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2023: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 14:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.9.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor security and bugfix release.</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Re-imported the ExtensionStorage js module for use by browser extensions.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the WebRequest module having erroneously un-processed build directives in it. This might have caused some subtle breakage.</li>
<li>Removed the use of high-resolution Windows system timers from the layout refresh driver; this should help with some performance and battery life issues.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where various parts of hardware acceleration weren&#39;t properly linked when changing the option from preferences.</li>
<li>If you have changed the preferences option to &#34;use hardware acceleration when available&#34; between 28.9.0 and this release, it is recommended that you go into preferences and toggle the option off/on to the preferred setting to correct any discrepancies.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with building the user-agent string using the build date as ID.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the release of document content viewers (CVE-2020-6819). <strong>DiD</strong></li>
<li>Fixed an issue with handling functions with rest parameters. <strong>DiD</strong></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 2 Defense-in-depth, 14 not applicable.</strong></p>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200408" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - April 8, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2024: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 18:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.9.0.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.0.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small bugfix update addressing 2 more important issues in 28.9.0:</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed an issue with browser migration and initialization code causing various browser run-time problems.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with cache behavior where some users would have trouble having their windows and tabs restored in &#34;soft refresh&#34; mode (see v28.9.0 release notes).<br/>
To solve this, we reverted to the previous (pull from cache) mode for now while we investigate the cause.</li>
</ul>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200324" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform - March 24, 2020</a> release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2025: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.0.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 13:53:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.9.0.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.0.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to address a problem with user-agent overrides not working as-intended for some people.</p>
<hr/>
<p dir="auto">Built with the <a href="https://github.com/MoonchildProductions/UXP/releases/tag/RELBASE_20200324" rel="nofollow">Unified XUL Platform @ RELBASE_20200324</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2026: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.0.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 20:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 28.9.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>New features:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented asynchronous iterators (<code>await iterator.next()</code> and <code>for await</code> loops) (ES2018)</li>
<li>Implemented promise-based media playback.</li>
<li>Implemented non-standard legacy <code>CSSStyleSheet</code> rules functions.</li>
<li>Implemented the html5 <code>&lt;dialog&gt;</code> element. To switch this on, flip <code>dom.dialog_element.enabled</code> to <code>true</code>.</li>
<li>Implemented the optional hiding of pinned tabs in CtrlTab/AllTab panes. (controlled through the preferences <code>browser.ctrlTab.hidePinnedTabs</code> and <code>browser.allTabs.hidePinnedTabs</code>)</li>
<li>Added 1.25x playback speed to html media elements.</li>
<li>Added a hidden pref (<code>browser.places.smartBookmarks.max</code>) to control the sizes of default smart bookmarks categories.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Aligned <code>document.open()</code> with the overhauled specification.</li>
<li>Aligned the way DOM styles are computed with mainstream browser behavior.</li>
<li>Removed the (unused) DOM promise implementation.</li>
<li>Enabled seeking to next frame in media files.</li>
<li>Enabled dynamic UA updates for emergency use.</li>
<li>Implemented rule processing stub for <code>font-variation-settings</code>.</li>
<li>Increased the maximum XML nesting depth to 2048 levels for extreme corner cases and to conservatively align with other browsers.</li>
<li>Improved the privacy of geolocation lookup calls, with thanks to a generous service donation from <a href="https://ip-api.com/" rel="nofollow">ip-api.com</a></li>
<li>Improved reporting of the operating system in site-specific user-agent overrides.</li>
<li>Improved table drawing performance again after the rewrite for sticky positioning making it slower.</li>
<li>Updated CSP processing to allow custom scheme wildcards to be specified without a port.</li>
<li>Aligned the behavior of outlines with other browsers when dealing with CSS-repositioned elements.</li>
<li>Changed the way hardware acceleration is controlled from the application.</li>
<li>Changed the default monospace font for main languages from <code>Courier New</code> to <code>Consolas</code>.<br/>
This provides a more balanced font for fixed-width text that is slightly more condensed and more in line with the naturally compacter variable-width fonts used everywhere else.</li>
<li>Changed the browser&#39;s behavior when restoring tabs from previous sessions. To prevent stale pages, it will now by default perform a &#34;soft refresh&#34; of the page instead of drawing it purely from cache without checking if the page needs updating. If you prefer the old behavior, set <code>browser.sessionstore.cache_behavior</code> to <code>0</code> in <code>about:config</code>.</li>
<li>Updated NSPR to 4.24 and NSS to ~3.48.1-RTM, removing the previous custom patch level with NSS being able to support custom rounds for DBM now.<br/>
For extensive release notes with all NSS changes, see <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Projects/NSS/NSS_Releases" rel="nofollow">NSS_Releases</a></li>
<li>Implemented an NSS performance optimization for Master Password use with limited effect.</li>
<li>Fixed some potential crashing scenarios with WebGL on Linux.</li>
<li>Completely removed <code>showModalDialog</code>.</li>
<li>Disabled some logging in production builds.</li>
<li>Removed various gadgeteering/redundant/dead DOM APIs (casting/presentation, FlyWeb)</li>
<li>Removed support for a number of critical libraries being system-supplied.</li>
<li>Removed &#34;Copy raw data&#34; button from the troubleshooting information page, since it&#39;s never used by us in that format, and users mistakenly keep using it instead of copying text.</li>
<li>Removed a bunch of Android and iOS support code.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with form elements sometimes being incorrectly disabled.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Captive Portal detection sometimes firing even when disabled by the user.</li>
<li>Performed various tree-wide code cleanups.</li>
<li>Backed out a large code cleanup patch for causing subtle issues in website operation (e.g. WordPress). This will have to be revisited later; the reintroduced code is not in use in practice.</li>
<li>Cleaned up the application updater code.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security-related fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a potential pointer issue issue in cubeb. DiD</li>
<li>Disabled allowing remote jar: URIs by default for security reasons. If you need this functionality for your non-standard environment, you can enable it with the preference network.jar.block-remote-files, but please consider moving away from this method of providing web-based applications.</li>
<li>Removed a potentially dangerous and otherwise ineffective optimization from the JavaScript engine.</li>
<li>Fixed unwanted behavior where created/focused pop-up windows could potentially cover the DOM fullscreen notification, hiding it from users. (CVE-2020-6810)</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where copying data as a curl request from developer tools would not properly escape parameters. (CVE-2020-6811)</li>
<li>Updated our sctp library code with several upstream fixes.</li>
<li>Unified XUL Platform Mozilla Security Patch Summary: 4 fixed, 3 already mitigated, 1 rejected, 11 not applicable.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2027: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/28.9.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 13:50:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.9.4</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.4_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This will be the final maintenance release of Pale Moon 27 on the &#34;Tycho&#34; platform. Do not expect any further updates.</p>
<p dir="auto">This is a security and usability update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated the useragent for addons.mozilla.org to work around their &#34;Only with Firefox&#34; discrimination preventing users from downloading themes, old versions of extensions, and other files with Pale Moon.</li>
<li>Restricted web access to the moz-icon:// scheme that could potentially be abused to infringe the user&#39;s privacy.</li>
<li>Prevented various location-based threats. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential vulnerability with plugins being redirected to different origins (CVE-2018-12364).</li>
<li>Improved the security check for launching executable files (by association) on Windows from the browser. For users who have (most likely accidentally) granted a system-wide waiver for opening these kinds of files without being prompted, this permission has been reset.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with invalid qcms transforms (CVE-2018-12366).</li>
<li>Fixed a buffer overflow using the computed size of canvas elements (CVE-2018-12359).</li>
<li>Fixed a use-after-free when using focus() (CVE-2018-12360).</li>
<li>Added some sanity checks on nsMozIconURI. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in the case the preferences file in the profile would not be writable (e.g. temporary permission issues due to backup, virus scanning or similar external processes).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">DiD This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code, e.g. when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem, or when new attack vectors are discovered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2028: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.4_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 21:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.9.3</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.3_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>(CVE-2017-0381) Ported a patch from libopus upstream. Note, contrary to that report, the libopus maintainers state they don&#39;t believe remote code execution was possible, so this was not a critical patch.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with task counting in JS GC.</li>
<li>Fixed a use-after-free in DOMProxyHandler::EnsureExpandoObject (thanks to Berk Cem Göksel for reporting).</li>
<li><strong>Portable only:</strong> Included the previously omitted registry helper. This may in some cases help with file/type associations.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2029: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.3_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 12:45:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.9.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and stability update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>We changed the language strings for softblocked items so people will cry less when we do our job.</li>
<li>(CVE-2018-5174) Prevent potential SmartScreen bypass on Windows 10.</li>
<li>(CVE-2018-5173) Fixed an issue in the Downloads panel improperly rendering some Unicode characters, allowing for the file name to be spoofed. This could be used to obscure the file extension of potentially executable files from user view in the panel.</li>
<li>(CVE-2018-5177) Fixed a vulnerability in the XSLT component leading to a buffer overflow and crash if it occurs.</li>
<li>(CVE-2018-5159) Fixed an integer overflow vulnerability in the Skia library resulting in possible out-of-bounds writes.</li>
<li>(CVE-2018-5154) Fixed a use-after-free vulnerability while enumerating attributes during SVG animations with clip paths.</li>
<li>(CVE-2018-5178) Fixed a buffer overflow during UTF8 to Unicode string conversion within JavaScript with extremely large amounts of data. This vulnerability requires the use of a malicious or vulnerable extension in order to occur.</li>
<li>Fixed several stability issues (crashes) and memory safety hazards.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2030: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 18:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.9.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a maintenance release.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Removed the unused/incomplete places protocol handler.</li>
<li>Worked around an issue with MSE media without a Track ID. This should help with the playability of some live streams.</li>
<li>Ported across jemalloc improvements from UXP.</li>
<li>Ported across cairo mutex improvements from UXP.</li>
<li>Added support for FFmpeg 4.0/libavcodec 58.</li>
<li>Added a fix for Windows 10&#39;s &#34;isAlpha()&#34; not being what one would expect in v1803.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2031: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 08:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.9.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is the last major development update for the v27 milestone (codenamed &#34;Tycho&#34;).<br/>
After this, we will be focusing our efforts for new features entirely on UXP and the new v28 milestone building on it. We will continue to support v27.9 with security and stability updates for a while, but no major new features will be added from this point forward.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a number of spec compliance issues in our media subsystem.</li>
<li>Added a trailing slash to referrers when policy is set to fix some web compatibility issues.</li>
<li>Fixed the property order in Object.getOwnPropertyNames(string) and others for web compatibility.</li>
<li>Updated RegExp(RegExp object, flags) to the ES6 standard specification.</li>
<li>Changed the embedded font from the no longer free EmojiOne to the open-licensed Twemoji (with additional fixes). This also further extends unicode support to Unicode 10 emoji(s). Please note that as a result, color emoji(s) will look different than before.</li>
<li>Adjusted some things in our memory allocator code to provide, among other things, better allocation alignment on Windows.</li>
<li>Made the attempt to migrate people from the old sync server domain name to the current one more aggressive. We will be retiring the old pmsync.palemoon.net Sync server address shortly to remove the need for us to maintain a security certificate for it; this preference migration should automatically put everyone on the correct server address when upgrading.</li>
<li>Made reading of the sessionstore synchronous, to speed up startup and prevent the homepage from being loaded when restoring a session.</li>
<li>Added a fix to switch to the correct window/tab when a web notification is clicked.</li>
<li>Changed the placeholder text to not include &#34;Search&#34; when all search functions from the address bar are disabled.</li>
<li>Enabled the use of Skia for canvas on Linux and OSX.</li>
<li>Worked around a potential cause for some non-standard bitmapped fonts ending up with incorrect line heights (I&#39;m looking at you, Noto fonts!).</li>
<li>Added a workaround for incorrectly-encoded JPEG-XR images with planar alpha. Ultimately, the jxrlib reference implementation should be fixed to encode according to spec.</li>
<li>Aligned XCTO:nosniff allowed script MIME types with the updated spec.</li>
<li>Improved the logic for storing vector images in the surface cache.</li>
<li>Fixed character set handling for XMLHttpRequests.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2032: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.9.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 11:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.8.3</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.3_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to solve a pervasive crash in responsive web layouts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2033: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.3_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 14:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.8.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Privacy fix: prevented update checks for the default theme.</li>
<li>Added a user-agent override for Dropbox to improve compatibility with their service.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with mouseover handling related to (CVE-2018-5103). <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Disabled the Mac OSX Nano allocator. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed (CVE-2018-5129) OOB Write.</li>
<li>Updated the lz4 library to 1.8.0 to solve potential issues. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed (CVE-2018-5137) Path traversal on chrome:// URLs</li>
<li>Fixed several memory safety an synchronicity hazards.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><em>DiD</em> This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code, e.g. when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem, or when new attack vectors are discovered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2034: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 11:23:54 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.8.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to address some breaking issues.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Backed out the NSPR/NSS update from 27.8.0 for causing crashes, general operational instability and handshake issues.</li>
<li>Disabled TLS 1.3 draft support by default, because with the NSS backout we only support an older draft right now that is no longer current and may cause connectivity issues. You can manually re-enable it at your own risk in <code>about:config</code> by setting <code>security.tls.version.max</code> to <code>4</code>.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2035: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 09:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.8.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a development update with new and improved features and bugfixes.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added support for emojis on Windows systems that have relatively poor support for them with standard font sets by including our own font (EmojiOne based for now).</li>
<li>Added a setting in preferences to select the use of tab previews with Ctrl+Tab.</li>
<li>Added Eyedropper menu entry to the AppMenu.</li>
<li>Added a preference to control whether the text cursor (caret) should be thicker when dealing with CJK characters or not (default = yes).</li>
<li>Added URL fix-ups for schemes (mis-typed &#34;ttp://&#34; etc.).</li>
<li>Added support for ES6 &#34;Symbol species&#34;.</li>
<li>Updated our TLS 1.3 support to the latest (probably final) draft.</li>
<li>Fixed gap inconsistency in the tabstrip.</li>
<li>Fixed a number of browser crashes.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash with the exponentiation operator &#34;**&#34;</li>
<li>Set the performance timer granularity to 1 ms.</li>
<li>Updated the kiss-fft library to our forked 1.4.0 version.</li>
<li>Disabled a potentially problematic optimization on Win 8+ with high contrast themes in use.</li>
<li>Removed the notification bar when in full screen to prevent unwanted visible screen elements.</li>
<li>Removed unmaintained and insecure WebRTC code - building with WebRTC enabled is no longer an option.</li>
<li>Removed redundant checks for &#34;Vista or later&#34; since that is all we support.</li>
<li>Added display of the http status to raw request displays.</li>
<li>Added a workaround for cloned videos not retaining their muted state.</li>
<li>Added a temporary workaround to avoid crashes on trackless media.</li>
<li>Removed some superfluous ellipses from menu labels.</li>
<li>Fixed undesired shrinking of line heights as a result of setting minimum font size in preferences.</li>
<li>Fixed some issues with setting the new tab preference (regression).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2036: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.8.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 16:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.7.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.7.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and stability update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed the X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff behavior to only check &#34;success&#34; class server responses, for web compatibility reasons.</li>
<li>Changed the perfomance timer resolution once more to a granularity of 1 ms, after evaluating more potential ways of abusing Spectre.<br/>
This takes the most cautious approach possible lacking more information (because apparently NDAs have been signed over this between mainstream players), follows Safari&#39;s lead, and should make it not just infeasible but downright impossible to use these timers for nefarious purposes in this context.</li>
<li>Improved the debug-only startup cache wrapper to prevent a rare crash.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in the XML parser.</li>
<li>Added a check for integer overflow in AesTask::DoCrypto() (CVE-2018-5122) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential race condition in the browser cache.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in HTML media elements (CVE-2018-5102)</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in XHR using workers.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash with some uncommon FTP operations.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential race condition in the JAR library.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">DiD This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code, e.g. when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem, or when new attack vectors are discovered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2037: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.7.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 10:38:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.7.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.7.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor emergency update to address website breakage and a theme issue.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added support for Array.prototype[@@unscopables].<br/>
Unfortunately, the addition of Javascript&#39;s ES6 Unscopables in 27.7.0 was incomplete, which caused a number of websites (e.g. Chase on-line banking, some Russian government sites) to display blank or not complete loading after updating to that version of the browser. This update should fix the problem by adding the missing part of the feature.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with the default theme causing tab borders to be drawn too thick at higher settings for visual element scaling (125%/150%) in Windows.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2038: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.7.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 15:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.7.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.7.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a stability and bugfix release, as well as adding a number of new features to further improve web compatibility.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Reorganized access to preferences (moved to the <code>Tools</code> menu on Linux, and renamed from <em>&#34;Options&#34;</em> to <em>&#34;Preferences&#34;</em> on Windows).</li>
<li>Renamed <em>&#34;Restart with add-ons disabled&#34;</em> to <em>&#34;Restart in Safe Mode&#34;</em> to better reflect what it does.</li>
<li>Worked around an issue with some improperly-encoded PNG files not decoding after our libpng update.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue on Mac builds not properly populating the application menu.</li>
<li>Added <em>&#34;My home page&#34;</em> as an option for new tabs.</li>
<li>Added an option to disable the 4th and 5th mouse buttons (Windows).<br/>
(<code>mouse.button4.enabled</code> and <code>mouse.button5.enabled</code>, respectively)</li>
<li>Improved the resetting of non-default profiles.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with details/summary having the incorrect height if floated, breaking layouts.</li>
<li>Implemented support for flex/columnset contents inside buttons to align its behavior with other browsers.<br/>
(this should fix layout issues with Twitch&#39;s new web interface)</li>
<li>Made several more improvements to the details/summary tags to align them with the current spec and fix several bugs.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where CSS clone operations would draw a border.</li>
<li>Changed the way fractional border widths are rounded to provide more natural behavior.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where number inputs would incorrectly be flagged as read-only.</li>
<li>Added assets for tile display in the Windows start panel.</li>
<li>Finished sync infra swapover by adding a one-time pref migration for server used.</li>
<li>Improved WebAudio API: Return the connected audio node from <code>AudioNode.connect()</code></li>
<li>Added support for a default playback start position in media elements.</li>
<li>Fixed an assert in cubeb-alsa code (Linux).</li>
<li>Added support for media cue-change events (e.g. subtitles).</li>
<li>Updated SQLite to 3.21.0.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when trying to use the platform embedded.</li>
<li>Fixed devtools (gcli) screenshots on vertical-text pages.</li>
<li>Fixed devtools copy as cURL for POST requests.</li>
<li>Improved the HTML editor component (several bugfixes).</li>
<li>Added support for ES7&#39;s exponentiation <code>a ** b</code> operator.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with arrow functions incorrectly creating an <code>arguments</code> binding.</li>
<li>Added Javascript&#39;s ES6 <code>unscopables</code>.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security/privacy fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Disabled automatic filling in of log-in details by default to prevent potential risks of credentials being abused (e.g. for tracking) or stolen.</li>
<li>Added a preference (in the category security) to easily enable or disable automatic filling in of log-in data.</li>
<li>Removed the sending of referrers when opening a link in a new private window.</li>
<li>Added an option to disable the page visibility Web API (<code>dom.visibilityAPI.enabled</code>), allowing users to prevent pages from knowing whether they are being actively displayed to the user or not.</li>
<li>Removed the <em>&#34;ask every time&#34;</em> policy for cookies. For granular control, please use any of the excellent available extensions to regulate cookie use on a per-site or per-url basis.</li>
<li>Added support for <code>X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff</code> (for scripts).</li>
<li>Changed the resolution of performance timers to a level where any future potential abuse for hardware-timing attacks becomes impractical. <em>DiD</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><em>DiD</em> This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code, e.g. when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem, or when new attack vectors are discovered.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2039: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.7.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 09:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.6.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.6.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and minor bugfix update to the browser.<br/>
This will most likely be the last update for 2017, with the holidays not far away.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented the concept of so-called &#34;cookie-averse document objects&#34; which is a security&amp;privacy measure that blocks certain web content from setting cookies. This mitigates cookie-injection, which might help against &#34;hidden&#34; cookie tracking.</li>
<li>Mitigated some domain name spoofing through IDN by using dotless-i and dotless-j with accents. (CVE-2017-7832)<br/>
Pale Moon will display these kinds of spoofed domains in punycode now in the actual address bar.<br/>
Please note that the identity panel will always be able to help you on secure sites when IDNs are in use to notice potential spoofing, as opposed to relying on detection algorithms in the URL itself. As such, some other issues like CVE-2017-7833 are already mitigated by us.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with mixed-content blocking. (CVE-2017-7835)</li>
<li>Added an extra check for the correct signature data type on certificates.</li>
<li>Added missing sanitization in exporting bookmarks to HTML. (CVE-2017-7840)</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes and memory safety hazards.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2040: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.6.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 17:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.6.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.6.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a minor bugfix release to address some pressing issues people have reported.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a regression with new windows (opening two windows from the command-line or file association, focus issues on new windows, not loading the home page in a new window, etc.)</li>
<li>Aligned XHR with the currect spec to allow withCredentials.</li>
<li>Fixed an input element focus issue within handlers.</li>
<li>Fixed the processing of all-padding HTTP/2 frames to prevent rare HTTP/2 hangups.</li>
<li>Updated CitiBank override to work around their login issues.</li>
<li>Updated Netflix override to a community-supplied one that seems to satisfy their arbitrary restrictions better.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2041: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.6.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 16:17:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.6.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.6.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major development update.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Dropped support for Direct2D 1.0 to avoid font rendering issues. Windows installations not capable of using Direct2D 1.1 will now fall back to software rendering. As a result, fonts may look different from this version onwards if you are on Windows Vista or Windows 7. Users on Windows 7 affected by this should install the Platform Update to re-enable Direct2D.</li>
<li>Updated the Brotli decoder library, and enabled support for Brotli HTTP content-encoding by default.</li>
<li>Added notifications to inform users about WebExtensions not being supported if they try to install them (as opposed to &#34;extension is corrupt&#34;)</li>
<li>Added a number of DOM <code>childNode</code> convenience functions. This should fix some lazy-loading frameworks.<br/>
(enjoy your LOLcats again!)</li>
<li>Changed automatic updates over to the new infrastructure.</li>
<li>Added extra proxy settings in Options, covering DNS lookups through SOCKS v5 and automatic proxy authentication with known credentials.</li>
<li>Added a selectable fallback character encoding of UTF-8 and fallback to UTF-8 as a last effort. (Issue <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/issues/1423" data-markdown-generated-content="" class="ref-issue" rel="nofollow">#1423</a>)</li>
<li>Improved timing of <code>canplay</code> and <code>canplaythrough</code> firing to work around a potential race condition locking up queued video playback.</li>
<li>Improved upmixing of mono sound for multi-channel setups.</li>
<li>Fixed a parallelization issue with the KISS-FFT library causing CPU-deadlocked threads (Issue <a href="https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/issues/1425" data-markdown-generated-content="" class="ref-issue" rel="nofollow">#1425</a>)</li>
<li>Fixed &#34;Remove from history&#34; function from the downloads panel.</li>
<li>Forced focus on the address bar in new windows if the content is a blank/empty document.</li>
<li>Fixed the dropmarker in the address bar to allow the suggestions to be closed with a click.</li>
<li>Further cleaned up the status bar code.</li>
<li>Disabled <code>window.showModalDialog</code>; it&#39;s been removed from the spec 2 years ago and has potential abuse issues (modal dialogs block the UI)</li>
<li>Fixed image decoder calls to make sure the image load event doesn&#39;t fire prematurely.</li>
<li>Updated LibPNG to 1.6.28, and enabled faster SSE2 decoding.</li>
<li>Updated WOFF2 code from upstream.</li>
<li>Updated the zlib compression library.</li>
<li>Made general improvements to internal code structure and spec adherence.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with certain command-line parameters being used.</li>
<li>Updated the default theme to improve consistency and contrast of toolbar and download buttons.</li>
<li>Increased the default duration of notification pop-ups and made them configurable.</li>
<li>Improved handling of audio-visual media (ongoing).</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in CSS where elements would sometimes reflow to the next line even with sufficient visual space.</li>
<li>Aligned the implementation of <code>for(let x=y;;)</code> loops with the final ES6 specification.</li>
<li>Fixed the selection system inside of a nested <code>contenteditable</code> element being broken.</li>
<li>Fixed Windows 10 detection for blocklisting graphics drivers.</li>
<li>Enabled pasting of clipboard data in documents without an editor element to improve web compatibility.</li>
<li>Fixed the uninstallation routine of restartless add-ons.</li>
<li>Fixed the handling of unimplemented functions in the console API.</li>
<li>Updated the Facebook user-agent to enable otherwise vendor-restricted functionality.</li>
<li>Updated the SVG scaling cache limit to be more lenient for larger SVG images at a small performance trade-off, working around some sites&#39; design issues.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security/privacy fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added an option to clear Site Connectivity Data (delete history).</li>
<li>Removed stale entries from the HSTS preload list, and improved generation/processing of it.</li>
<li>Removed undesired certificate issuer organization to common name fallback (if issuer org is empty).</li>
<li>Added pretty-printing for ECDSA-SHA224, 256, 384 and 512 hashed certificate signatures.</li>
<li>Worked around some more issues with broken Apple fonts.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2042: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.6.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 12:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.5.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.5.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a security and stability update to the browser, as well as fixing some issues users have indicated.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed the default Windows 10 styling when no accent color is aplied to black-on-white.</li>
<li>Changed the theme styling on Windows 10 when the system window frame is used (menu bar enabled) to use the window manager background directly, preventing visual lag updating the window color when it changes.</li>
<li>Updated user agent overrides for DropBox, YouTube and Yahoo to work around user agent sniffing issues.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash in the media subsystem.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression where video playback hardware acceleration was disabled incorrectly on some systems.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated libhyphen to the latest upstream code to fix a security issue.</li>
<li>Updated NSPR to 4.16-RTM with a patch to un-bust building on win64.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.32.1-RTM.</li>
<li>Worked around some more issues with Mac fonts (CVE-2017-7825).</li>
<li>Fixed a potential rooting hazard in NPAPI plugin code. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed a potential reference issue in JavaScript arrays. <em>DiD</em></li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><em>DiD</em> This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2043: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.5.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 08:25:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.5.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.5.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major update furthering general development of the browser.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>User interface:
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added a menu option to restart the browser.</li>
<li>Added Windows-specific CSS parameters and queries for the use of the system accent color. Added are parameters -moz-win-accentcolor and -moz-win-accentcolortext, and the media query -moz-win-accentcolor-applies to know if Windows is actively using an accent color.</li>
<li>Changed Windows&#39; browser CSS sheet ot use variables instead of hard-coding colors, simplifying its style and making it more flexible. Further cleaned up the Windows 10 specific browser style.</li>
<li>Changed the theme on Windows 10 to use the new accent colors and improve O.S. consistency.</li>
<li>Fixed some general inconsistencies in the Windows theme on all Windows operating systems.</li>
<li>Updated Windows widgets to be able to pick up Windows 10 accent colors dynamically and have the browser &#39;s look and feel respond accordingly, even with automatic color changes based on desktop wallpaper.</li>
<li>Removed the experimental FF4 prerelease status-in-addressbar feature because the already-crowded address bar needs a break. This should solve some extension interop issues, theme issues and domain highlighting issues people have reported.</li>
<li>Cleaned up some dead code for the plugin updater that no longer exists.</li>
<li>Fixed a text direction issue in preferences.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with disabled context menu entries after using Customize...</li>
<li>Reorganized and cleaned up the status preferences.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Media:
<ul dir="auto">
<li>MSE Media updates (ongoing). We are focusing on improving MP4 handling.</li>
<li>Improved MP3 metadata parsing (e.g. incorrect duration with embedded album cover)</li>
<li>Fixed a number of searching issues in MP3 files</li>
<li>Fixed a few crashes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with automatically exporting bookmarks to HTML on shutdown.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression re: domains allowed to/blocked from installing add-ons.</li>
<li>Fixed several internal errors thrown in the front-end.</li>
<li>Fixed several minor issues in the devtools.</li>
<li>Added a fix to prevent the home page from being loaded (and subsequently overridden) when restoring a session.</li>
<li>Added an option to control add-on blocklist behavior (Options -&gt; Security)</li>
<li>Added DOM function <code>isSameNode()</code>.</li>
<li>Added DOM <code>onvisibilitychange</code> event.</li>
<li>Added <code>document.scrollingelement</code> (CSSOM).</li>
<li>Added a basic implementation of <code>Object.values</code> and <code>Object.entries</code> enumerator functions (ECMA2017 draft).</li>
<li>Added &#34;Open in new private window&#34; to bookmarks, feeds and history entries.</li>
<li>Added HTTP request method OPTIONS.</li>
<li>Added an option to exit to a no-content page after encountering a network or security error.<br/>
This is controlled with the preference browser.escape_to_blank -- when set to true, &#34;Get me out of here&#34; buttons will load a blank page instead of the browser&#39;s home page.</li>
<li>Added experimental Brotli accept-encoding (alternative to gzip/deflate compressed http data transfer). Disabled by default for now because it causes issues.</li>
<li>Improved the handling of several CSS selectors.</li>
<li>Changed session storage to remember form data for https sites by default.</li>
<li>Added (yet another) trap prevention method to <code>onbeforeunload</code> events.</li>
<li>Fixed privacy preferences not correctly resetting all options when choosing &#34;Remember History&#34;</li>
<li>Fixed not being able to deselect loading bookmarks in the sidebar.</li>
<li>Limited the display of user names and hosts in the http auth dialog to sane lengths, preventing over-sizing issues.</li>
<li>Fixed a number of potential crash points.</li>
<li>Improved the security of the Windows dll loader module.</li>
<li>Reinstated &#34;Open all in tabs&#34; option on folders of live bookmarks (feeds).</li>
<li>Made URL matching more liberal in selected text to make it easier to open stated addresses.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Graphite font rendering where automatic font collision fixing didn&#39;t always work.</li>
<li>Color Management for images is now disabled by default on Linux, due to many distributions not having a streamlined setup with sane default ICC profiles, which makes images look worse when color management is enabled.</li>
<li>Tightened the update security check to prevent acceptance of update manifests that have been intercepted/replaced through https MitM attacks.<br/>
Please be aware that https-filtering antivirus may interfere with future application updates as a result.</li>
<li>Updated the ANGLE library to broaden WebGL support and reduce the potential of crashes (due to junk being sent to the video driver).</li>
<li>Added content-sniffing for WebP images (working around CloudFront&#39;s incorrect content-type headers).</li>
<li>Fixed a problem with some H.264 media not playing (SPS NAL).</li>
<li>Improved timer efficiency (switch back to lower precision when high precision is no longer needed, reducing CPU/power consumption).</li>
<li>Improved context search on selected text/links.</li>
<li>Updated address bar handling with Alt or Shift modifiers, so that &#34;switch to tab&#34; with a modifier can open copies of already-opened sites.</li>
<li>Added a fix on Linux for starting the browser from Enlightenment.</li>
<li>Privacy fix: Pale Moon will now clear QuotaManager storage (asm.js cache/IndexedDB data) as part of clearing Offline Website Data.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2044: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.5.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 21:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.4.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.4.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to address some security and stability issues.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed a number of crashes.</li>
<li>Enabled the opt-in debugging feature to log SSL keys to a file in all builds.</li>
<li>Added a fix for TLS 1.3 handshakes causing a browser hangup.<br/>
Handshakes should be considerably faster now and no longer stall in the wrong circumstances.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated NSPR to 4.15.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.31.1.</li>
<li>Fixed a DoS issue using overly long Username in URL scheme (CVE-2017-7783)</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where (cross domain) iframes could break scope (CVE-2017-7787)</li>
<li>Fixed an issue in WindowsDllDetourPatcher (CVE-2017-7804)</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with elliptic curve addition in mixed Jacobian-affine coordinates (CVE-2017-7781)</li>
<li>Fixed a UAF in nsImageLoadingContent (CVE-2017-7784)</li>
<li>Fixed a UAF in WebSockets (CVE-2017-7800)</li>
<li>Fixed a heap-UAF in RelocateARIAOwnedIfNeeded (CVE-2017-7809) <em>DiD</em> (accessibility is disabled)</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><em>DiD</em> This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2045: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.4.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 20:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.4.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.4.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to address a few media and web issues:</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed an issue where MSE media playback would not use hardware acceleration when it could, causing choppy playback and high CPU usage.</li>
<li>Fixed ES6 iterator chains to be spec-compliant.</li>
<li>Fixed ES6 vector append calls and some related memory leaks.</li>
<li>Added a workaround to reduce the chances of a rare crash occurring.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2046: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.4.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2017 12:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.4.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.4.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major update to straighten out most of the media streaming issues, as well as adding the necessary enhancements, bugfixes and security fixes to the browser.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Completely re-worked the Media Source Extensions code to make it spec compliant, and asynchronous as per specification for MSE with MP4. This should fix playback problems on YouTube, Twitch, Vimeo and other sites that previously had some issues. A massive thank you to Travis for his tireless work on making this happen!<br/>
Please note that MSE+WebM (disabled by default) is not using this new code yet (planned for the next release), and as such there is a temporary set of things to keep in mind if you don&#39;t use default settings:
<ul dir="auto">
<li>If you have previously enabled MSE+WebM, this setting will be reset when you update to avoid conflicting settings with the updated MSE code.</li>
<li>We&#39;ve added an extra setting in Options to disable the updated MSE code (asynchronous use) in case you need to use WebM or are otherwise having issues with the updated code (please let us know in that case).</li>
<li>Once again, the MSE+WebM and Asynchronous MSE use are currently mutually exclusive. You can have one or the other, not both, until we sort out the code for WebM. To enable MSE+WebM you will first have to disable Asynchronouse MSE in settings (otherwise the WebM setting will be greyed out and disabled).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Added a control in options/preferences for HSTS and HPKP usage.</li>
<li>Changed HTML bookmark exports to write CRLF line endings to the file on Windows.</li>
<li>Leveraged multi-core rendering for libVPX (VP8/VP9 WebM decoding).</li>
<li>Fixed some issues accessing DeviantArt (useragent-sniffing).</li>
<li>Aligned CSS text-align with the spec.</li>
<li>Added a recovery module for browser initialization issues (e.g. when using a wrong language pack).</li>
<li>Fixed spurious console errors for XHR requests with certain http response codes.</li>
<li>Enabled v-sync aligned refresh for a smoother scrolling experience.</li>
<li>Removed support for CSS XP-theme media queries.</li>
<li>Improved console error reporting.</li>
<li>Fixed resetting toolbars and controls from the safe mode dialog.</li>
<li>Fixed bookmark recovery option from the safe mode dialog.</li>
<li>Fixed <code>innerText</code> getters for display:none elements.</li>
<li>Fixed a GL buffer crash that might occur with certain combinations of drivers and hardware.</li>
<li>Added some more details to about:support.</li>
<li>Fixed a potential crash when the last audio device is removed during playback.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash on about:support when windowless browsers are created.</li>
<li>Updated <code>&lt;select&gt;</code> elements to blank if the actively set value doesn&#39;t match any of the options.</li>
<li>Updated the interpretation of 2-digit years in date formats to match other browsers: 0-49 = 2000-2049, 50-99 = 1950-1999.</li>
<li>Added <code>q</code> units to CSS (quarter of a millimeter).</li>
<li>Added <code>.origin</code> property to blobs.</li>
<li>Fixed several minor layout issues.</li>
<li>Fixed disabled HTML elements not producing the proper JS events.</li>
<li>Implemented web content handler blacklist according to the spec, allowing more than feeds to be registered.</li>
<li>Fixed a spec compliance issue with <code>execCommand()</code> on HTML elements.</li>
<li>Fixed a problem with table borders being drawn uneven or being omitted when zooming the page.</li>
<li>Added devtools &#34;filter URLs&#34; option in the network panel.</li>
<li>Added visual sorting options to the Network inspector.</li>
<li>Added importing of login data from Chrome profiles on Windows (Chrome has to be closed first).</li>
<li>Added importing of tags from bookmark export files (HTML format).</li>
<li>Updated usage of SourceMap headers with the updated spec (<code>SourceMap</code> header, keeping <code>X-SourceMap</code> as a fallback).</li>
<li>Fixed several cases of wrongly-used negations in JS modules.</li>
<li>Added the <code>auxclick</code> mouse event.</li>
<li>Added a control to not autoplay video unless it is in view (<code>media.block-play-until-visible</code>).</li>
<li>Updated the Graphite font library to 1.3.10.</li>
<li>Updated how image and media elements respond to window size changes (responsive design).</li>
<li>Added parsing and use of rotation meta data in video.</li>
<li>Fixed several crashes in a number of modules.</li>
<li>Fixed performance regression for scaling large vector images (e.g. MSIE Chalkboard test) <span class="emoji" aria-label="party popper">🎉</span></li>
<li>Fixed some issues with notification icons.</li>
<li>Fixed some internal errors with live bookmarks.</li>
<li>Updated SQLite to 3.19.3.</li>
<li>Fixed several reported issues with devtools (cli-cookies, cli help, copying cURL, inspecting SVGs, element size calculations, etc.)</li>
<li>Fixed an issue where a server response was allowed to override add-ons&#39; specified version ranges even for add-ons that have strict compatibility (e.g. themes, language packs).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Removed preloading of HPKP hosts and enabled HPKP header enforcement.</li>
<li>Added support for TLS 1.3, the up-next secure connection protocol. <span class="emoji" aria-label="party popper">🎉</span></li>
<li>Fixed an issue with TLS 1.3 not supporting renegotiation by design.</li>
<li>Relaxed some restrictions for CSP to temporarily work around web compatibility issues with the CSP-3 deprecated <code>child-src</code> directive.</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.28.5.1-PM to address some security issues.</li>
<li>Updated the installer selfextractor module to address unsafe loading of libraries.</li>
<li>Changed the way certain resources are included to reduce effectiveness of some common fingerprinting techniques. (e.g. browserleaks.org)</li>
<li>Fixed a regression in the display of security information in the page info dialog for insecure content.</li>
<li>Fixed two potential issues with allocating memory for video. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with the network prediction algorithm. <em>DiD</em></li>
<li>Restricted the use of Aspirational scripts in IDNs to prevent domain spoofing, in anticipation of the UAX#31 update making this official.</li>
<li>Prevented a Mac font specific issue that could be abused for domain spoofing (CVE-2017-7763)</li>
<li>Fixed several potentially exploitable crashes. (CVE-2017-7751) (CVE-2017-7757) and some that do not have a CVE designation.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2047: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.4.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.3.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.3.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">A major development update. Many things have changed in the media back-end, but please understand that some things are still a work in progress, and you may still encounter some html5 video playback issues with MSE.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed up, checked and enabled vertical text writing modes!<br/>
Pale Moon will now be able to display vertical, right-to-left script.</li>
<li>Added the option to reset non-default profiles.</li>
<li>Fixed various issues in the WebP image decoder.</li>
<li>Added internally-supported document types to allowed  types.</li>
<li>Fixed locale selection in ICU after update to ICU58.<br/>
(Note: Pale Moon uses the system locale for date formatting, not the browser locale)</li>
<li>Re-implemented the previous spellchecker dictionary logic (allow user override of document/element language, improve logic and make it unambiguous).</li>
<li>Ongoing fixes for the MP4 parser and MSE.</li>
<li>Made HTML Media Elements&#39; preload attribute MSE-spec compliant.<br/>
The preload attribute on HTML media elements is now ignored in the case of an MSE source. This prevents an issue with sourceopen not firing when preload=&#34;none&#34;.</li>
<li>Fixed some issues with Windows WMF media playback.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with Synced preferences sometimes overwriting stored individual preferences.</li>
<li>Fixed display of RSS folder icons.</li>
<li>Fixed issues with custom context menus.</li>
<li>Fixed an issue importing bookmarks with separators losing their extra data.</li>
<li>Changed the way numeric addresses are handled in the address bar so it doesn&#39;t perform a search when it shouldn&#39;t.</li>
<li>Added an option (browser.sessionstore.cache_behavior) to control from which source restored tabs pull their page content:<br/>
0 = load restored tab data from cache (current behavior, default)<br/>
1 = refresh restored tab data from the network<br/>
2 = refresh stored tab data from the network and bypass any cached data.</li>
<li>Improved upon a v27 performance regression with SVG scaling.</li>
<li>Improved performance by being more selective which CSS animations to process.<br/>
As a side-effect, elements changing their display from &#34;none&#34; to something visible now also animate.</li>
<li>Increased memory allocation for the use of very large PAC files.</li>
<li>Added menu entries for the permissions manager and improvements to its function and display.</li>
<li>Added preferences to control &#34;highlight all&#34; behavior of the find bar:<br/>
accessibility.typeaheadfind.highlightallbydefault = true/false highlight all found words by default.<br/>
accessibility.typeaheadfind.highlightallremember = true/false remember the last-used state of Highlight All.</li>
<li>Added devtools command-line options.</li>
<li>Added remote IP and protocol to Devtools-&gt;Network entry details.</li>
<li>Added support for <details> and <summary> HTML tags.</summary></details></li>
<li>Fixed a regression in the MSIE profile migrator.</li>
<li>Removed migration of browser-specific settings when migrating data from IE/Safari.</li>
<li>Implemented optional parameters for permessage-deflate in preparation for RFC7692 errata making acceptance of them mandatory (and to prevent web compat issues due to the current conflicting text of it).</li>
<li>Made the image document favicon skinnable.</li>
<li>Aligned DOM selection addRange with the spec.</li>
<li>Exposed mozAnon constructor js binding to system scopes for XHR.</li>
<li>Enhanced form data handling from JavaScript.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security/privacy changes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated NSS to 3.28.4-RTM to address a number of issues.</li>
<li>Added support for RSA-AES(-GCM)-SHA256/384 suites to broaden compatibility.</li>
<li>Reconfigured networking security: disabled static DHE suites by default, enabled all RSA-AES(-GCM)-SHA256/384 suites in their stead.</li>
<li>Fixed referrer policy keyword to align with the current spec (&#34;cross-origin&#34; vs &#34;crossorigin&#34;).</li>
<li>Added an option to display punycode domain for IDN websites to combat phishing.<br/>
This is enabled by default for domain-validated https sites.<br/>
Preference: browser.identity.display_punycode<br/>
0 = Display IDN name in identity panel (previous behavior)<br/>
1 = Display punycode name for DV SSL domains (default)<br/>
2 = Also display punycode for HTTP sites if IDN name used</li>
<li>Fixed an issue to prevent contacting remote servers when a connection might get blocked.</li>
<li>Fixed 3 public security flaws in libevent, which may affect Mozilla-based products. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed several memory- and thread-safety hazards.</li>
<li>Fixed an address bar spoofing issue. (CVE-2017-5451)</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable crash with HTTP/2. (CVE-2017-5446)</li>
<li>Fixed several security hazards in XSLT processing. (CVE-2017-5438) (CVE-2017-5439) (CVE-2017-5440)</li>
<li>Fixed several security hazards in old protocols. (CVE-2017-5444) (CVE-2017-5445)</li>
<li>Fixed out-of-bounds access in text formatting. (CVE-2017-5447)</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable issue with innerText. (CVE-2017-5442)</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable issue in graphite font shaping.</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable crash with credential-authentication.</li>
<li>Fixed out-of-bounds access with text selection in rare cases.</li>
<li>Fixed a security hazard in the ANGLE library.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2048: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.3.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 17:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.2.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.2.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update to fix some stability and usability issues.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Fixed an issue with planar alpha handling (transparency) when drawing JXR images.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash related to a change JavaScript array handling introduced in 27.2.0.<br/>
This became apparent with the pentadactyl extension, but could happen in other situations as well.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash when opening ridiculously large images with HQ scaling enabled (default).<br/>
Pale Moon will now only apply HQ scaling for images within reasonable limits (64 Mpix or smaller). Images larger than that may not display properly when zooming in, or may not display at all, even scaled down (e.g. &gt;256 Mpix large) and show a &#34;broken image&#34; placeholder instead; please use dedicated image viewer applications for those kinds of images; it is outside the scope of a web browser to handle such large images.</li>
<li>Changed the way URL hashes are handled, and will no longer %-decode anchor hash identifiers by default.<br/>
Note that this is against RFC 3986, which states that any part of the URL scheme that isn&#39;t data should be decoded.<br/>
This is required for web compatibility because several sites use hash links to pass actual data to web applications (Please don&#39;t do this! Hashes ar part of the URL address, should only consist of &#34;safe&#34; characters, and aren&#39;t suited to pass arbitrary data) and the most common browsers no longer follow the RFC in that respect.<br/>
If you want RFC compliance, switch <code>dom.url.getters_decode_hash</code> to <code>true</code></li>
<li>Restored 2 RSA Camellia cipher suites that were missing: TLS_RSA_WITH_CAMELLIA_128_CBC_SHA and TLS_RSA_WITH_CAMELLIA_256_CBC_SHA</li>
<li>Fixed an issue with custom toolbars getting deleted during upgrade from 27.0/27.1 to 27.2</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2049: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.2.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 20:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.2.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.2.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a major update to the browser with a focus on back-end improvements and security.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Updated the ICU lib to 58.2 to fix a number of issues.</li>
<li>Added proper control for the user for offline storage for web applications.</li>
<li>Added a check to prevent auto-filled URLs from copying the autofilled selection to clipboard/primary.</li>
<li>Added the feature to pass a URL to open in a private window from the command-line.</li>
<li>Improved the display of the downloads indicator on the button in bright-text situations.</li>
<li>DOM storage now honors the &#34;3rd party cookie&#34; setting in that it will not allow 3rd party data to be stored if 3rd party cookies are disallowed.</li>
<li>Allowed toolbar button badges to be properly styled.</li>
<li>Updated the hunspell spellchecking library to 1.6.0 to fix a number of issues.</li>
<li>Fixed desktop notifications being off-screen if fired in rapid succession.</li>
<li>Added Element.insertAdjacentElement and Element.insertAdjacentText DOM functions.</li>
<li>Added support for JPEG-XR images.<br/>
This makes Pale Moon have the broadest support for image formats of all web browsers.<br/>
(enabled by default; you can disable this with media.jxr.enabled).</li>
<li>Completely removed the use of GStreamer on Linux.</li>
<li>Added support for element.innerText</li>
<li>Custom toolbars should now properly remember their state</li>
<li>Fixed some more playback issues with MP4/MSE videos.<br/>
Please be aware that we are still working on further improving MSE video handling.</li>
<li>Changed media processing to reduce dangerous processing asynchronicity.<br/>
This should also make media elements and playback more responsive.</li>
<li>Fixed a useragent string regression always displaying the minor Goanna version as .0</li>
<li>Updated NSPR to 4.13.1</li>
<li>Updated NSS to 3.28.3-RTM</li>
<li>Fixed unrestricted icon sizes in PMkit buttons</li>
<li>Fixed unresponsive buttons on support page when not building the updater</li>
<li>Fixed the use of &#34;View image&#34; and &#34;Save image as&#34; on extremely large images</li>
<li>Changed the way &#34;View Image&#34; and &#34;Save image as&#34; work on canvas elements.</li>
<li>Made checking for dangerously large resolution PNG images smarter.<br/>
It will now accept larger &#34;strip&#34;-aspect ratio images while reducing unsupported large image resolutions.<br/>
This will e.g. fix Gmail&#39;s &#34;emoji&#34; window that uses a ridiculously long but very narrow single image to store all the emoticon pictures.</li>
<li>Converted several hard-coded URLs to preferences.</li>
<li>Updated the google.com override so it would not cripple services based on UA sniffing.</li>
<li>Added Inner and Outer Window ID administration.</li>
<li>Fixed the add-on discovery pane detection.</li>
<li>Added support for canvas ellipse.</li>
<li>Improved drawing of certain MathML elements at problematic zoom levels.</li>
<li>No longer building gamepad support.</li>
<li>Updated Harfbuzz font shaper to 1.4.3 to fix a number of issues.</li>
<li>Fixed a number of crashes (layout, plugins, uncommon navigation, bad URLs).</li>
<li>Aligned SVG specular filters with the spec.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security/privacy changes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Added support for 256-bit AES-GCM encryption</li>
<li>Added support for ChaCha20-Poly1305 encryption</li>
<li>Removed support for Camellia-GCM since nobody seems interested in it<br/>
(Camellia in 128/256-bit CBC block mode is still fully supported)</li>
<li>Added support for SHA-224, SHA-256, SHA-384 and SHA-512 to Crypto utils</li>
<li>Improved status handling of secure sites to be less sensitive to &#34;insecure&#34; items that are local.</li>
<li>Fixed print preview hijacking (CVE-2017-5421)</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially exploitable crash in OnStartRequest (CVE-2017-5416)</li>
<li>Fixed potential cross-origin content-stealing through a timing attack (CVE-2017-5407) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a denial-of-service problem with view-source (CVE-2017-5422)</li>
<li>Fixed crash in directional controls (CVE-2017-5413)</li>
<li>Fixed a perceived problem with chrome manifests (CVE-2017-5427)</li>
<li>Fixed the use of an uninitialized value (CVE-2017-5405)</li>
<li>Fixed a buffer overflow (CVE-2017-5412)</li>
<li>Fixed a UAF situation (CVE-2017-5403)</li>
<li>Fixed a potential spoofing issue with the address bar (CVE-2017-5417)</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue in libvpx (CVE-2017-5402) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential issue with HTTP auth (CVE-2017-5418)</li>
<li>Fixed several memory safety hazards and potentially exploitable crashes DiD</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">DiD This means that the fix is &#34;Defense-in-Depth&#34;: It is a fix that does not apply to a (potentially) actively exploitable vulnerability in Pale Moon, but prevents future vulnerabilities caused by the same code when surrounding code changes, exposing the problem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2050: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.2.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 11:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.1.2</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.1.2_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a small update adding a workaround for potential deadlocks happening in media elements.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2051: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.1.2_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 11:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.1.1</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.1.1_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto">This is a stability and bugfix update to the browser.</p>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Implemented a fix in media handling to prevent crashes with concurrent videos and/or rapidly starting/stopping video playback in the browser.</li>
<li>Fixed the way the Adobe Flash plugin is detected to prevent confusion with other plugins that identify themselves as &#34;Flash&#34; (e.g. VLC).</li>
<li>Windows: Solved stability issues caused by the release build process, resulting in unexpected behavior (e.g. hangups).</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2052: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.1.1_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 11:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pale Moon 27.1.0</title>
      <link>https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.1.0_Release</link>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="auto"><strong>Changes/Fixes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Reworked the media back-end completely (thanks Travis!) to use FFmpeg (including support for FFmpeg v3 and MP3 playback) and our own MP4 parser, and no longer relying on gstreamer on Linux, as well as adding some improvements on Windows for media parsing and playing.</li>
<li>On Linux, Apple .mov files of the correct type will also be played through FFmpeg now, for those rare occasions where they are still in use.</li>
<li>Restored classic about:config styling.</li>
<li>Added a fallback to US-ASCII if the autoconfig UTF-8 conversion fails.</li>
<li>Improved cross-compartment wrapper handling when managing a large number of tabs (performance).</li>
<li>Changed the way audio and video synchronization is calculated to account for (slow) device latency, preventing things from getting out of sync.</li>
<li>Changed the way scripts are handled when they are stopped from the &#34;unresponsive script&#34; dialog, to prevent browser lockup. We will now stop all scripts in the affected compartment in one go.</li>
<li>Fixed several errors in the devtools.</li>
<li>Fixed a nasty crash caused by cross-origin referrers.</li>
<li>Fixed the installer to allow 64-bit versions of the browser to be installed on Vista.</li>
<li>Added HTML5-spec clipboard handling for content (cut&amp;copy only -- paste is not allowed for security reasons).</li>
<li>Made multiple changes to the jetpack modules to cater to PMkit extensions.<br/>
This should make running SDK-based modules as PMkit extensions fairly simple for extension developers.</li>
<li>Fixed a css layout issue: make max-width affect contributions to intrinsic min-width.</li>
<li>Implemented several updates to the permissions manager. Among others, Improved the permissions manager (about:permissions) with a more complete set of permissions for pages.</li>
<li>Removed Metro browser platform/widget code.</li>
<li>Removed support for non-standard/deprecated let blocks and expressions.</li>
<li>Made the use of let as a keyword versionless and ES6 compliant.</li>
<li>Made the privacy category in preferences a tabbed setup to better fit the current options.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression preventing certain MP4 video files from playing.</li>
<li>Fixed a regression where seeking in media files would halt playback/jump to the end of the stream.</li>
<li>Fixed a crash caused by certain downloadable fonts with DirectWrite in use.</li>
<li>Improved downloads-button indicator legibility on some combinations of Windows versions and system theme colors.</li>
<li>Changed the Facebook user-agent override to be our native one, based on reports from users that it is (finally) working acceptably.</li>
<li>Fixed the general useragent override taking priority over site-specific overrides.</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto"><strong>Security/privacy changes:</strong></p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Changed CORS handling to allow data: sources, assuming they are same-origin. This should fix the infamous &#34;Facebook endless reload&#34; issue and may make some other sites that assume this particular (unspecified) CORS behavior happy with Pale Moon.</li>
<li>Reinstated the network.stricttransportsecurity.enabled preference so people who choose privacy over HSTS can do so again.</li>
<li>In HSTS &#34;off&#34; state, prevented HSTS site status from being written to disk.</li>
<li>Updated the IDN blacklist with more extended unicode characters that &#34;look very similar to&#34; normal ASCII characters, to prevent spoofing of well-known domains. If blacklisted characters are found, the IDN domain name will be displayed in its punycode form. (CVE-2017-5383 and similar)</li>
<li>Fixed an exploitable crash when using MP4 video. (CVE-2017-5396)</li>
<li>Fixed an exploitable crash in XSL parsing. (CVE-2017-5376)</li>
<li>Fixed a potential security issue when exporting certificates with specially-crafted credentials. (CVE-2017-5381)</li>
<li>Fixed a potential use-after-free situation in frame selection. (CVE-2017-5380) DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a leak of window details through the Ion compiler in certain situations.</li>
<li>Fixed the potential for an exploitable crash involving Javascript GC. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potential overflow situation in (non-released) WebRTC code. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed a potentially unsafe situation in websockets. DiD</li>
<li>Fixed several memory and other safety hazards (1318766, 1325877, 1328834 DiD, 1288561 DiD, 1322420 DiD, 1293327 DiD, 1322315, 1325344, 1285960).</li>
</ul>
<p dir="auto">DiD = Defense-in-Depth patch</p>
]]></content:encoded>
      <author>Moonchild</author>
      <guid>2053: https://repo.palemoon.org/MoonchildProductions/Pale-Moon/releases/tag/27.1.0_Release</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 05:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>